《赛艇男孩》
字幕:Dex7er  公众号:值得看的
Press.
用力
Legs through.
蹬腿
Stay together.
保持一致
As one.
同步
In. Through.
破水 划
Legs through.
蹬腿
Oh, man!
天啊
What the heck?
搞什么鬼？
I swear that boy's gonna be the death of me.
我发誓那小子会要了我的命
Every time I fix it, he rips it again.
每次我修好了, 他又会撕掉
西雅图 华盛顿州 1936年
Engineering design is different
工程设计和其他创意领域
from other areas of creativity
有点不同
in that, you must be able to actually build
在这一点上, 你必须有能力真正建造出
what you imagine.
你的创意
And then make sure it works as you designed.
然后确保它按照你的设计方式运行
The design process is structured to help direct
设计过程有助于结构化引导
your creativity.
你的创造力
Now, uh...
现在...
What kinda engineer you wanna be?
你想成为哪种工程师？
I'm thinking mechanical for me, 'cause I like building things.
我想当个机械工程师, 因为我喜欢造东西
- Mm-hmm. - You wanna partner up on...
- 嗯哼 - 你想成为...
Something you two gentlemen would like to share with us?
两位先生有什么想和我们分享的吗？
Or can I continue?
或者我可以继续了吗？
Sorry.
对不起
- Thank you. - Awesome. Thank you.
- 谢谢 - 好极了 谢谢
Okay, I just need one more.
好吧, 我还要一个人
Let's see.
让我看看
Uh, you.
你
That's all I need today, fellas. Sorry.
今天就到这儿吧 伙计们 对不起
- Morning. - Morning.
- 早安 - 早上好
This was in my box this morning.
这是我今天早上收到的
Okay, it looks like you still owe a balance
好吧, 看来你还欠着本学期的
on this semester.
一点学费
Yeah, well, I paid half already
对, 我已经付了一半了
and they said I could pay the other half later.
他们说我可以稍后再付另一半
Afraid later has arrived, Mr. Rantz.
兰茨先生, 恐怕已经到期了
Maybe a part-time job would help.
也许干点兼职会有帮助
I've been looking.
我一直在找
Well, there's a board down the hall.
走廊尽头有一块公告牌
I can give you two weeks.
我可以给你延期两周
After that, you will need to consider
之后, 您就需要考虑
other educational options.
其他的教育选项了
Thanks.
谢谢
It's a waste of time. I called every number up here.
浪费时间 我打遍了这里所有的电话
And that nanny job,
甚至那份保姆工作都问过
all filled before semester even started.
在学期开始前就已全部招满了
I check every day to get a jump on a new one,
我每天都来查查, 想抢个新机会
but there hadn't been any.
但是一个机会都没有
I'm staying with my aunt till I can afford a place.
在我租得起房子之前, 我只能住在姑妈家
I spend half my day pulling cat hair off of my clothes.
每天都要花上半天时间从衣服上扯猫毛
I hate cats.
我讨厌猫
You like 'em?
你喜欢吗？
Cats, I mean.
我是说猫
I, uh, never thought much about 'em.
我, 呃, 从来没怎么考虑过它们
I hate 'em.
我讨厌他们
Thought I saw you in class.
我想我在课堂上见过你
- You remember me? - Mm-hmm.
- 你还记得我吗？- 嗯
All right. Then, what's my name?
好吧 那我叫什么名字？
Uh, Joyce Simdars.
乔伊斯·西姆达斯
- And you're Joe Rantz. - Uh-huh.
- 你是乔·兰兹 - 嗯哼
I remember because you had a huge crush on me
我记得, 因为四年级的时候
in the fourth grade.
你暗恋我来着
- No, I didn't. - Yeah, yeah, you did.
- 不, 我没有 - 你有
You made me this pretty little card
你给我做了张漂亮的小卡片
with some flowers stuffed in it.
里面夹着几朵小花
Right before my family went away to Olympia.
就在我家搬去奥林匹亚之前
- Uh... - Are you one of those people
- 啊 - 你是那种一紧张就
who can't eat when you're nervous?
吃不下东西的人吗？
- I'm not nervous. - No?
- 我没紧张 - 没？
So, what are you doing here, Joe?
那么, 你在这里做什么, 乔？
I'm trying to learn, uh, engineering.
我在这学习, 呃, 工程学
Hmm.
嗯
I'm gonna be a teacher.
我要当老师
Mostly here just to get away from home, though.
不过, 来这里主要还是为了离家远点
You remember my mother?
你还记得我妈妈吗？
Sorta. Always had a Bible in her hand.
算是吧 她手里总是拿着本《圣经》
Yeah.
是啊
Unless she's throwing it at you.
除非她扔过来砸你
You like rowboats?
你喜欢划艇吗？
You know, like, paddlin' 'em.
你知道的, 坐在上面划水那种
- Who's this? - I'm Roger.
- 你是谁？- 我是罗杰
Hi, Roger. I'm Joyce.
嗨 罗杰 我是乔伊斯
This is Joe, but he's not real talkative right now
这是乔, 但他现在不太爱说话
'cause he's a little bit nervous.
因为他有点紧张
- No, I'm not. No, I'm not. - He is a little nervous.
- 不, 我没有 我没有 - 他有点紧张
I'm not nervous.
我不紧张
We might be able to make some money if you can row.
如果你会划, 我们也许能赚点钱
- Joyce, you ready? - Oh. Gotta go, boys.
- 乔伊斯 好了吗？- 哦 得走了 孩子们
Nice seeing you again, Joe.
很高兴再次见到你, 乔
Roger.
罗杰
By the way,
顺便说一句
did you ever get over that crush?
你从那段暗恋中走出来过吗？
Come on, let's go.
来吧, 我们走
She's a looker, huh?
她很好看 是吧？
So, what's that about making some money?
那么, 赚钱是怎么回事？
Yeah, the rowing team.
对, 赛艇队
You're on it, you get a part-time job
只要进了队, 你就算得到了一份兼职
including a cheap place to live.
还包括一个便宜的住的地方
I could get free of them cats.
我就可以摆脱那些猫了
All you gotta do is make the team.
你要做的就是进队
How hard can that be?
这有什么难的？
How many make the team?
有多少人能进队？
Hey, how many, uh...
嘿, 有多少, 呃...
How many fellas get picked?
要选多少人？
Eight, I think.
我想是八个
Eight?
八个？
What's he say?
他说什么？
He didn't know.
他不知道
All right, listen up.
好了, 听着
I'm Coach Ulbrickson.
我是乌尔布里克森教练
Well, that's Coach Bolles,
那是博尔斯教练
Coach Brown.
布朗教练
Now, you're all here because we're looking
现在, 你们来这里, 是因为我们正在遴选
for the eight most qualified young men to fill out JV boat.
八名最有资格的年轻人来组成初级队
That means most of you will not be chosen.
这意味着你们中的大多数人都不会被选中
In fact, the majority of you will most likely
事实上, 你们中的大多数人很可能会
walk away on your own within the next few weeks,
在接下来的几周内自行离开
'cause your bodies will hurt,
因为你们的身体会受伤
minds will tire,
精神会疲倦
and you'll decide this dream of yours
你会认定你要与世界上
to compete against the greatest crews in the world
最优秀的赛艇选手同台竞技的梦想
is just not worth it.
就是不值得的
There's no shame in that.
这并不丢人
Eight-man crew
八人赛艇
is the most difficult team sport in the world.
是世界上最难的团队运动
The average human body is just not meant for such things.
普通人的身体根本无法承受这些
It's just not capable of such things.
根本做不了这种事
But average is not gonna get a seat on my boat.
但普通人是不可能在我的艇上找到座位的
So, good luck.
所以, 祝你好运
Okay. Fall into two lines.
好的 分成两队
Registration on the left. Uniforms on the right.
左边是注册生 右边是自费生
That was a beautiful speech, Coach.
说得真好, 教练
- Name? - Uh, Joe Rantz.
- 姓名？- 乔・兰兹
Joe, you ever crewed before?
乔, 你以前当过艇员吗？
Uh... Um...
呃...呃...
Row. You ever rowed before?
划艇 你划过艇吗？
No. No. Uh...
不, 不, 呃...
How much does the job pay once you're on the team?
入队后这份工作的薪水是多少？
Go pick up your gear over there.
去那边拿你的装备
- To your right. Next. - Name?
- 去右边 下一个 - 姓名？
Roger Morris.
罗杰·莫里斯
Roger, you ever crewed before?
罗杰, 你以前当过艇员吗？
No.
不
All right.
好的
Pick up your gear across the way.
到对面领装备
You'll be divided into groups
你们将被分成几个小组
and rotate through training stations.
并在训练坞进行轮换
When you hear your number called, follow the coach.
叫到自己的号码时, 跟着教练走
One through 16, you're with me,
1 到 16 号, 你们跟着我
17 through 32 with Coach Matthews,
17 到 32 跟着马修斯教练
33 to 48 with me.
33 至 48 号跟我
Line up.
排好队
You got any idea what we're in for?
你知道我们要干什么去吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
Good. Me either.
很好 我也是
One through 16, come on.
1 到 16 号, 快点
The average adult man is capable
一般成年男子有能力
of taking in roughly four liters of oxygen per minute.
每分钟吸入大约四升氧气
An oarsman must be able to consume as much as eight.
一个桨手必须达到八个人的消耗量
You have to teach your bodies to do that.
你必须让你的身体学会这种能力
- We'll do 50 push-ups,
- 我们做 50 个俯卧撑
followed by 50 sit-ups and 50 jacks.
然后是 50 个仰卧起坐和 50 组往返跑
We'll keep doing sets of 50
我们将继续做 50 组
till it's time to change stations.
直到换训练坞的时候
Eight on each side.
每边八个
Feet in stretchers.
脚放在踏板上
Lace 'em up.
系上鞋带
Let's take Old Nero out.
让我们把老尼禄号划出去
All right, on my count, straight backs, use your legs.
好了, 听我口令, 挺直腰板, 用你的腿
Twelve! Don't just slap the water. Roll your wrists.
12 号！别光拍水 转动你的手腕
Up, down.
起, 躺
Four, five, six, seven,
四 五 六 七
eight, nine, ten.
八 九 十
Stroke, two, three, four.
一 二 三 四
Catch, drive, finish, recovery.
入水 推进 完成 归位
Next station. Everybody out.
到码头了 所有人下艇
Up, down.
起, 躺
Switch!
交换
All set?
都准备好了吗？
Up, down.
起, 躺
There's four parts to a stroke, gentlemen,
运桨分四个步骤, 先生们
not three, okay?
不是三个, 好吗？
Catch, drive, finish, and recovery.
入水 推进 完成 归位
You can't skip any of 'em.
一个都不能少
And you know why we're not going in a straight line?
你们知道我们为什么没走直线吗？
'Cause number 22 here
因为 22 号
is the only one that's listening to me.
是这里唯一一个在听我说话的人
Catch, drive,
入水 推进
finish, recovery.
完成 归位
That's better.
这样好多了
All right. Let's pick up the pace to 18.
好的 让我们加快节奏到 18 拍
Lot of tall timber in this bunch, Coach.
这里有很多好木材啊 教练
Few boys there could even push your varsity crew.
那边的孩子几乎没有能比得上你们校队的
It's hard to judge off one day.
才第一天 还很难说呢
Still, you had to see enough
不过, 你还要看到什么
to make you almost finally crack a smile?
才能让你开怀大笑？
Yeah, I'll let you know at the end of the season, huh?
赛季结束后我会告诉你的, 啊？
Olympic year, this year,
奥运年, 今年
so ideally, they'll stretch longer than most.
所以假如理想的话, 他们的训练时间要比以往更长
Olympic year? I didn't realize.
奥运年？我都没有意识到
I spoke with Coach Ebright down in Cali.
我在加州大学和埃布莱特教练谈过了
He's sure aware of it.
他肯定意识到了
Feels good about his chances, too.
他对自己的机会也很有信心
Oh, yeah?
哦, 是吗？
Any first impressions you'd like to see in print?
有什么第一印象想报道出来的吗？
You know I don't read the paper, Royal.
你知道我不看报纸的, 洛伊尔
Excuse me, Coach.
对不起, 教练
If you're looking for tips, you're gonna have to get 'em
如果你想问诀窍, 那就与其他人一样
in practice like everybody else.
在训练中去找吧
No, sir. I was just wondering how much this paid.
不 先生 我只是想知道会给多少工资
Say again?
再说一遍？
They said there was a job included if you make the team?
他们说, 如果能入选, 还能得到一份工作？
I just need to know if it's gonna cover
我只想知道够不够支付
the rest of my tuition.
我剩下的学费
Yeah, I'm sure it will.
是的, 我肯定是够的
Hey, you just concentrate for now on making the squad, son.
嘿, 你先集中精力看能不能入选吧 孩子
Thank you, sir.
谢谢你, 先生
Now, there's a question I bet
现在, 我打赌这个问题
those Ivy League coaches never get.
那些常春藤联盟的教练们永远也不会遇到
Speakin' of,
说到
I sure hope this year goes better than the last.
我当然希望今年能比去年更好
No one's rooting for your boys more than me.
没有人比我更支持你的孩子们了
- Good luck, Coach. - And you, Royal.
- 祝你好运, 教练 - 你也是, 洛伊尔
Did you go grab some food?
你去吃东西吗？
Ah, I'm not hungry.
啊, 我不饿
I got enough for us both if you want it.
如果你想要吃的话, 我拿的足够我们俩吃的
Not that hungry.
没那么饿
I'll see you later.
回头见
I appreciate it.
我很感激
There you go.
给你
- Here you go, sir. - Thank you.
- 给你 先生 - 谢谢
How's your chicken?
鸡肉怎么样？
Great. Thanks.
很不错 谢谢
Yeah, that's a pork chop you're eating.
是吗, 你吃的是猪排
Ah.
啊
Sorry.
对不起
So, I saw Royal Brougham today.
所以, 我今天见到了洛伊尔·布鲁姆
And he made sure to tell me
他还特意告诉我
that Ky Ebright's squad is strong this year.
凯·埃布莱特的球队今年实力强劲
Cal is always strong.
加州大学队一直很强的
And you always worry.
而你一直在担心
How'd your new boys look?
这帮新孩子们看起来怎么样？
Well, it's too early to say.
现在下结论还为时过早
There's definitely a lot of 'em.
人倒是有很多
That's good. Nice big stable to choose from.
很好 有这么大的马场可供选择
- If enough of them last. - The best ones will.
- 如果有足够多的能坚持到最后 - 最好的就会
- Just like you did. - Mm.
- 就像你一样 - 嗯
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了？
Nothing, just a little stiff.
没什么, 只是有点僵硬
Yeah, looks it. How come?
嗯 看到了 怎么搞的？
Rowed boats till it almost killed us.
划艇划到我们差点没命
What?
什么？
Page 43 in your texts.
课本第 43 页
So, in solving the framework,
因此, 在解决框架问题时
what does it mean to reflect?
反射意味着什么？
Excuse me, young man.
对不起, 年轻人
Would you like me to speak quieter so you can rest?
要不要我小声点, 好让你休息？
I feel like that's maybe a trick question.
我感觉这可能是个陷阱问题
- Quiet!
- 安静
Pay attention or go home to sleep.
要么专心听讲, 要么回家睡觉
You can't do both in here.
你不能在这睡大觉
You're welcome, Joe Rantz.
不客气, 乔·兰茨
Thank you.
谢谢
Three.
三
Four.
四
Push, then pull. Push...
推, 然后拉 推...
Up, down!
起, 躺
48 and 12 on the bow.
48 号和 12 号在艇头
Yeah. I'm thinkin'...
是的, 我想...
What about Morris in the six behind Rantz?
把莫里斯放在兰茨身后的六号位？
Keep time with me.
跟上我的节奏
Stroke, two, three, four. Stroke, two...
一 二 三 四 一 二...
Come on, boys! Who wants it more?
来吧, 孩子们！谁更想要？
Keep driving those legs!
继续蹬腿
Do not let 22 beat you!
不要让 22 号打败你！
You still remember me?
你还记得我吗？
Mm-hmm.
嗯
Wasn't sure.
不确定
Haven't seen you much lately.
最近很少见到你
I just been busy with stuff.
我只是一直在忙事情
- Rowing stuff? - Mostly.
- 赛艇？- 大部分是
Hmm.
嗯
I heard Roger say that they're announcing the team today.
我听罗杰说, 他们今天要公布队员名单
Are you gonna make it?
你能进吗？
There's lot of guys tryin'.
有很多人都想进
You wanna take me on a boat ride when you do?
等你进了 你想带我去坐艇兜风吗？
Sure.
当然
Gentlemen,
先生们
I wanna thank you all for comin' out
感谢大家参与
and giving your best effort.
并全力以赴
Every single one of you left standing
你们留在这里的每一个人
has performed admirably.
都有令人钦佩的表现
Unfortunately, only a few of you can be chosen to continue.
遗憾的是, 你们中只有少数人可以被选中留下来继续
Coach Bolles.
博尔斯教练
Hume.
休谟
Hunt.
亨特
McMillin.
麦克米伦
Day.
戴
Morris.
莫里斯
White.
怀特
Adam.
亚当
Rantz.
兰茨
Coy, you're the reserve.
科伊 你是替补
We thank the rest of you for your time and your effort.
感谢你们付出的时间和努力
All right, then.
那好吧
Go and celebrate.
去庆祝吧
I will see you on the water tomorrow.
明天水上见
Well done.
干得好
That's my favorite part.
这是我最喜欢的部分
Come on, boys.
来吧, 孩子们
Let's go.
我们走吧
Now lift 'em up.
现在把浆举起来
It's all this guy talks about, his Dodge.
这家伙满嘴都是他的道奇
Hey, listen, I've done so much rowing.
嘿, 听着, 我划得太多了
I knew you'd made it.
我就知道你会入选的
I'm glad one of us did.
我很高兴我们中有个人做到了
Ah, you were always in the bag.
啊, 你的入选一直都是稳的
When Coach called my name, my knees almost buckled.
当教练叫到我的名字时, 我的膝盖差点跪下了
I wonder what seats they'll put us in.
不知道他们会给我们安排什么位置
I just want the stroke.
我只想坐在领桨手的位置上
That's Hume's seat. Guaranteed.
那是休姆的位置 我打包票
Hey, you're not a mute, are you?
嘿, 你不是哑巴吧？
'Cause I've never once heard you say nothin'.
因为我从没听你说过一句话
No.
不是
He doesn't need to talk, the way he pulls that oar.
像他那样划桨 他不需要会说话
Yeah, Chuck, maybe you should pull more and talk less,
是啊, 查克, 也许你应该多划桨少说话
you want that stroke seat.
如果你想坐那个领桨手座位
I don't care where they put me,
我不在乎他们把我放在哪里
as long as I'm in there somewhere.
只要我在就行
We're all in there somewhere.
我们都会在的
Yeah.
是啊
Bow down to Washington
向华盛顿鞠躬
Mighty are the men who wear the purple and the gold
穿金戴银者威风凛凛
Joyfully we welcome them within the victor's fold
我们高兴地欢迎他们加入胜利者的行列
We will carve our names in the Hall of Fame
我们将把自己的名字刻在名人堂里
To preserve the memory of our devotion
为了保留我们奉献的记忆
So, heaven help the foes of Washington
所以, 上天保佑华盛顿的敌人
They're trembling at the feet of mighty Washington
他们在强大的华盛顿脚下瑟瑟发抖
Our boys are there with bells, Their fighting blood excels
我们的小伙子在那里敲钟 他们的战斗血性出类拔萃
It's harder to push them over the lines than pass...
把他们推过界线比通过....
- Hey. - Hi.
- 嘿 - 嗨
You, uh...
你...
You wanna go for a boat ride?
你想去赛艇上坐坐吗？
Now?
现在？
Yeah.
是啊
Yeah, okay.
好吧
Catch, drive,
入水 推进
finish, recovery.
完成 归位
You gotta do all four before you can start again.
在重来一遍之前, 你必须做完所有四个步骤
That's better. You gotta feather next.
好多了 下一步你要翻桨了
Feathering? What's feather?
翻桨？什么是翻桨？
Here, look.
看这里
You roll your wrists
你滚动你的手腕
to spin the oar.
转动艇桨
- You see? - Mm.
- 看到了吗？- 嗯
Now, try again.
现在, 再试一次
You're a natural.
你是天生的
I thought you said you were gonna take me on a boat ride.
我以为你说要带我坐着艇兜风去
All right, scooch over.
好吧, 坐过去点
All right.
好的
Do you like it? Rowing?
你喜欢吗？划艇？
Well,
还行
gettin' a job out of it.
得到一份工作
And a room. So, I guess.
还有一个房间 所以 我猜
Who else made the team?
还有谁入选了？
Roger, Shorty, some others.
罗杰 矮子和其他一些人
You know, they put the races on the radio.
你知道, 他们会在广播里播报比赛
Everybody listens.
每个人都在听
Yeah, they took, uh, some photos.
他们拍了一些照片
- Asked a bunch of questions. - What kinds of questions?
- 问了一堆问题 - 什么样的问题？
It's just, you know,
就是, 你知道
where we're from, stuff like that.
我们来自哪里, 诸如此类的
Did you tell them the truth?
你告诉他们事实了吗？
Mm. Mostly.
嗯 差不多吧
You're all gonna be famous.
你们都会出名的
Then you really will forget about me.
然后你就真的会忘记我了
I don't think I could if I tried.
就算我想, 我觉得我也做不到
You get to row us back to shore.
你得把我们划回岸上
We have class in the morning.
我们早上还有课
- Which bed you want? - Couldn't care less.
- 你想要哪张床？- 我不在乎
Oh, nice.
哦, 不错
We get to keep these, right?
我们可以留着这些, 对吗？
Long as we stay on the team.
只要我们还在队里
Each seat on the boat has its own purpose.
艇上的每个座位都有自己的用途
Like eight separate parts of one great racehorse.
就像一匹高大赛马身上的八个独立部位
Morris in one, Day in two,
莫里斯在一号, 戴在二号
and Adam in the three.
亚当在三号
Your technique will keep the boat on its proper course.
你们的技术要让艇保持正确的航向
And four, five, and six are like the engine room.
而四 五 六就像是引擎舱
That is the power.
这是力量源泉
White, McMillin, and Hunt.
怀特 麦克米伦和亨特
Now, Rantz is our seven.
现在, 兰茨是我们的七号
So, you set the pace with Hume, the stroke.
所以, 你和休姆, 领桨员, 一起设定节奏
And every good racehorse has a jockey.
每一匹好赛马都有一个骑师
Glenn Morry...
格伦·莫里...
Come on, Glenn.
来吧, 格伦
is our coxswain.
是我们的舵手
Now, he calls the strategy
现在, 他指挥的策略
set up by myself and Coach Bolles.
是由我和博尔斯教练设定的
He'll give you rein when he wants you to run,
他想让你们跑的时候, 就会给你们松缰绳
he'll pull you back to slow you down.
他会把缰绳拉紧 让你们慢下来
And when the time is right, he'll get out his whip.
一旦时机成熟, 他就会拿出鞭子
Hey, fellas.
嘿, 伙计们
Okay, time to get in the water.
好了, 该下水了
Let's go again!
我们再来一次！
Hey, junior boat,
嘿, 菜鸟队
you tired after your first day?
第一天 累吗？
He'll never make it. Don't take it so hard.
他不会成功的 别这么认真
Hey, where you going? Come back.
嘿, 你去哪儿？回来
I hate those assholes.
我讨厌那些混蛋
You gotta learn to pace yourself.
你得学会掌握自己的节奏
- It's Joe, isn't it? - Mm-hmm.
- 乔 对吧？ - 嗯哼
Most of you boys don't have an interest in a boat
你们大多数人都对艇不感兴趣
until you can sit in it.
直到你坐在里面
You like to work with wood?
你喜欢做木工活吗？
Yeah, my father did some.
是的, 我父亲做过一些
He used to make things.
他以前会做些东西
Nothing like this, just porches and stuff.
不是这种, 就是门廊之类的东西
I helped him fix up an old canoe once.
有一次, 我帮他修好了一艘旧独木舟
I'm sure he and your mother must be very proud of you now.
我相信他和你的母亲现在一定为你感到非常骄傲
Making the team.
加入赛艇队
This is for you boys.
这是给你们的
Your racing shell.
你们的比赛艇
Always welcome to give me a hand with it.
随时欢迎你来帮我一把
If you find some free time.
如果你有空的话
No, I didn't mean right now.
不, 我不是说现在
You should rest up tonight.
你今晚应该好好休息
I'm okay.
我没事
Technique is more important than power.
技术比力量更重要
You have to be able to pull a perfect oar,
你必须学会划出完美的桨法
stroke after stroke.
一桨接着一桨
It's called swing.
所谓摇摆
When all eight are rowing in such perfect unison
当八个人全都划得如此整齐划一
that no single action
没有任何一个动作
is out of sync with the rest of the boat.
和艇上其他人的不同步
Then you aren't fighting each other.
这样你们的力量就不会互相抵消了
You're moving with less effort.
艇跑起来更省力
Each one of your strokes is worth
你划出的每一桨都相当于
one and a half of the other boat's.
另一艘艇的一桨半
Most crews never find it.
大多数艇员从未领略过
But when they do,
但当他们领略到时
rowing is more poetry than sport.
赛艇与其说是一项运动, 不如说是一首诗
White and Day, switch.
怀特和戴, 交换位置
Rantz, Adam,
兰茨, 亚当
switch back.
换回来
Row!
划！
- Row! - Come on!
- 划！- 来吧
Row! Row through the lake!
划！划过湖面
Row! More!
划！用力
What, did you forget everything you learned
怎么, 你们把最近三年学过的东西
in the last three years?
都忘了吗？
Brown, you're still skying.
布朗, 你还在划空
Billings, are you the stroke? You're rushing.
比林斯, 你是领桨员吗？你在赶
You have seven men behind you, all chasing the boat.
你身后有七个人, 都被你带得很赶
34 strokes.
34 桨
You're fine at 34 strokes.
你们划 34 桨没问题
Anything higher and you fall apart.
再高一点 你们就崩溃了
34 strokes, you don't beat Cal.
34 桨, 你们赢不了加州大学
34 strokes,
34 桨
you don't win at Poughkeepsie.
在波基普西你们赢不了
You certainly don't get to Germany.
你们肯定去不了德国
You know who you beat with 34 strokes?
你们知道 34 桨能打败谁吗？
The JV boat.
初级队
Maybe.
只是可能
What are you guys waiting for? Get back in the boat.
你们还在等什么？回到艇上去
You guys, you're gonna get back out there
你们, 你们要回到那里去
and you're gonna do it again until you get it right!
然后再做一次, 直到做对为止！
Hope I'm not intruding, Al.
希望我没有打扰你, 艾尔
Not at all, Ben. Come on in. Take a seat.
不 本 进来吧 请坐
Great timing.
正是时候
Just going through the equipment budget
刚好在查看准备送交贵委员会的
to send over to your committee.
设备预算
Nothing unreasonable.
没什么不合理的
Some pieces for the gymnasium.
体育馆的一些部分
And the five-year-old uniforms
还有五年前的制服
are startin' to look a little ragged.
看起来有点破旧
Ah, we'll see what we can do.
啊, 我们会尽力的
Committee's meeting next week.
委员会下周要开会
More wins usually means more money from the alumni.
赢得越多通常意味着校友资助就越多
Sure.
当然
So, how are our boys doing, Coach?
我们的小伙子们怎么样了, 教练？
Early to say, but solid.
现在说还为时尚早, 但很可靠
Oh, they've been workin' hard.
哦, 他们一直在努力训练
My boy, Bo, had 'em training
我儿子, 波, 他们整个休赛期
- all off season. - Hmm.
- 都在训练 - 嗯
Think they're gonna make a real run at Cal this year.
我认为他们今年会向加州大学发起真正的冲击
I hope we can.
我希望我们能做到
We got a good junior boat to push 'em, too. You should...
我们也有一个不错的初级队在训练 你应该...
It'd be nice to finally hang a banner up at our place
如果可以在我们这挂上横幅 而不是让加州大学
instead of letting Cal have 'em all.
把它们都拿走 那就太好了
We'll do our best, sir.
我们会尽力的, 先生
And an Olympic medal to go with it.
还有一枚奥运奖牌可以拼一拼
Bo says his boat's got a shot.
波说他们队有机会
If we work hard.
如果我们加把劲
And catch some breaks.
并取得一些突破
Winners make our own breaks in life, Coach.
教练, 人生的突破都是赢家自己创造的
And we need this.
我们需要这个
It's now or never.
机不可失, 时不再来
Hmm.
嗯
"If we shadows have offended"
"如果我们这些影子冒犯了你"
"Think but this, and all is mended."
"那么只需想象 这一切都是梦境"
"That you have but slumbered here..."
"你只是在这里打了个盹..."
"While these visions did appear."
"而这些幻象就出现了"
Thank you.
谢谢
It's some fella called Shakespeare, right?
是一个叫莎士比亚的, 对吗？
You know, music people
你知道, 搞音乐的
should have to take care of their own trash.
他们应该收拾好自己的垃圾
Better than the cafeteria last night.
比昨晚自助餐厅好多了
I mean, God, I almost couldn't eat today.
我是说, 天哪, 我今天差点吃不下饭
You see that old food, all mushed around like that?
你看到那些食物了吗，都被弄成那样了？
You ever notice how under the girls' tables,
你有没有注意到女孩们的桌子下面
it's always the worst?
总是最糟糕的？
When you look close, girls are nasty.
你仔细看, 女孩们都很邋遢
You don't realize it 'cause of their nice dresses
你没发现, 只是因为她们穿着漂亮的裙子
and their hair's all fixed up.
头发都梳得好好的
But I'll clean under 10 boys' tables before I do one...
但我宁愿清理 10 个男孩的桌子下面 也不...
Oh, Don, there anything you can't do?
哦, 唐, 还有什么是你不会的吗？
Keep goin'.
继续弹啊
Ain't we got fun?
我们玩得开心吗？
The rent's unpaid, dear
房租还没付呢, 亲爱的
We haven't a car
我们没有车
In any way, dear
无论如何, 亲爱的
We'll stay as we are
我们乐天知命
Even if we owe the grocer
即使我们欠杂货店老板的钱
Ain't we got fun?
我们玩得开心吗？
What about Morris in the six behind Rantz
莫里斯在兰茨身后的六号位怎么样？
and Hunt in the one?
让亨特在一号位？
We tried that last week.
我们上周试过了
I don't know.
我不知道
On paper, this should work.
从纸面上看, 这应该是可行的
Better than just work.
不止是可行
You put them in singles against 100 other kids,
你让他们和其他 100 个孩子进行单人比赛
I'd bet on that being the top eight finishers out there.
我敢打赌, 前八名的选手都在这里
That's the problem.
这就是问题所在
They have a hard time remembering
他们很难记住
they aren't in sculls, especially Rantz.
他们不是在参加双桨比赛, 尤其是兰茨
They're a strong a group as I've ever seen
他们是我在这里见过的
come through here
最强大的队伍
and they might also be the worst crew I've ever seen.
他们可能也是我见过的最糟糕的艇员
It's a bad mix.
这是一个糟糕的组合
It's my fault.
是我的错
Well, maybe those names aren't the problem.
也许这些名字并不是问题所在
Sometimes young horses need a louder jockey.
有时, 年轻的马匹需要一个声音更大的骑师
- You wanted to see me, Coach?
- 你想见我, 教练？
Close the door.
关上门
Sit down, Bobby.
坐下 鲍比
You know why I called you here?
你知道我为什么叫你来吗？
My guess is you need someone to help you beat Cal.
我猜你需要有人帮你打败加州大学
Let me explain something to you.
我来给你解释一下
I'm giving you a second chance.
我给你第二次机会
You're gonna drive the JV boat.
你要来驾驶初级队的艇
- JV? - Yeah, that's right.
- 初级队？- 没错
Now, listen to me.
现在, 听我说
You're gonna do what I tell you, when I tell you.
我让你做什么你就得做什么
And if I see you goin' off on your own, then you're out.
如果我看到你还是一意孤行, 你就出局了
For good this time. You understand?
这次是永远 你明白吗？
- Yeah, I do. - All right.
- 明白 - 好吧
Get out.
出去吧
Come on!
来吧
Your hands are too high!
你的手太高了
Fix the catch.
解决入水问题
One catch, let's go.
同时入水, 我们走
Look like a team, fellas.
像个团队, 伙计们
Legs through, eyes up.
蹬腿 抬头
Legs through.
蹬腿
You guys are out of sync. Find Hume.
你们不同步 跟着休姆
Take it off Hume.
跟着休姆的节奏
Watch those blade heights.
注意桨片高度
Hey, Rantz, you with us? Get with Hume.
嘿, 兰兹, 你和我们一起吗？跟着休姆的节奏
Legs through.
蹬腿
Legs through. Come on!
蹬腿 来吧
Day, you're catching too high. Lower.
戴, 你入水太高了 低一点
Morris, you're late.
莫里斯, 你迟了
Enough! Way-nuff! Way-nuff!
够了 停桨 停桨
Yeah, good ride.
是啊, 划得不错
And my favorite part is how my nuts vibrated
我最喜欢的部分就是 当你们在不同时间入水的时候
when you guys were all hitting the water at different times.
我的蛋蛋都被震飞起来了
We were moving slow as shit, but the sensation was nice.
我们慢得跟屎一样, 但感觉很舒服
Screw you, Moch.
去你的, 莫奇
No, dandy, you're the one screwed.
不, 花花公子, 你要倒霉了
Coach told me if you guys
教练告诉我, 如果你们
don't get yourselves figured out,
不把自己的问题解决了
you're not only missing the regatta,
你不仅要错过下一场比赛
you're not racing at all this year.
你们今年都不会参加比赛
That's a whole hell of a lot of work
如果什么都不参加
to just do nothing with.
那可真是无用功了
So, feel like trying it again?
那么, 想再试一次吗？
I'm ready.
我准备好了
That's good.
很好
Always with the grain.
总是顺着纹路
How's the crew coming along?
艇员们进展如何？
Lot harder than I expected.
比我预想的要难得多
Well, that's what practice is for.
这就是练习的目的
Coaches will have you ready for the regatta.
开赛前教练会把你们调整好的
Your folks gonna make it?
你的家人会来吗？
My mother, she passed when I was young.
我妈妈在我很小的时候就去世了
And my pop, he had to move off
而我爸爸, 他几年前就搬走了
several years ago to find work.
为了工作
Kinda lost touch.
失联了
Who brought you up?
谁把你养大的？
Pop figured I was okay on my own.
爸爸觉得我一个人没问题
Hmm.
嗯
How old were you?
你当时多大？
Almost 14.
差不多 14.
Him and my stepmom,
他和我继母
they had two young boys to care for.
他们有两个年幼的儿子需要照顾
There was no work around Sequim.
塞奎姆附近没有工作
Worked out best for everybody.
这样对大家都好
Legs through.
蹬腿
Legs through. Soften the shoulders.
蹬腿 放松肩膀
Eyes up.
抬头
Stay loose.
保持放松
Shoulders down, Joe.
肩膀放低 乔
Stay low.
放低
Stay loose.
放松
Eyes up.
抬头
Better?
好点了吗？
As one.
同步
Put the pressure in the footplate.
把压力给到脚踏板上
Drive!
推进
Here she is, boys.
她来了, 孩子们
Maybe the finest George has ever made.
也许这是乔治有史以来最出色的杰作
Now, this is your new home.
现在, 这就是你的新家
Treat her that way.
好好对待她
Care for her. Protect her.
照顾她 保护她
Most of all, you better respect her.
最重要的是, 你最好尊重她
All right, suit up and get out there.
好了, 穿戴整齐, 出发吧
You race against Cal in a week.
你们一周后要和加州大学比赛
Won't let you down, Coach.
不会让你失望的, 教练
Welcome to a beautiful day at Lake Washington
欢迎来到美丽的华盛顿湖畔
for the annual showdown between the Washington Huskies
观看华盛顿哈士奇队
and the Cal Bears of Berkeley in the Pacific Coast Regatta.
和伯克利的加州熊队在太平洋海岸帆船赛上的年度对决
And just as it has been for the past 30 years,
和过去 30 年一样
the two-mile race will extend from Sand Point
两英里长的比赛将从沙角开始
up to Sheridan Beach.
直到谢里登海滩
We have 100,000 race fans gathered here
我们这里聚集了 10 万名赛艇迷来观看
for what is sure to be another maritime battle
这肯定是一场自新奥尔良比赛以来
the likes of which we haven't seen since New Orleans.
我们从未见过的海上战斗
And in the purple and gold, Washington Huskies coach,
身穿紫金战袍的华盛顿哈士奇队主教练
Al Ulbrickson, is bringing back a strong senior team
阿尔·乌尔布里克松将带来一支强大的高级队
and an inexperienced junior boat,
和一艘没有经验的初级艇
in hopes of reversing a devastating season last year.
希望扭转上个赛季的糟糕表现
Without a doubt, he's facing stiff competition.
毫无疑问, 他面临着激烈的竞争
Legendary Coach Ky Ebright has once again
传奇教练凯·埃布莱特再次
brought two strong boats.
带来了两艘强艇
He's called his junior crew
他夸赞他的初级艇员为
possibly the best young oarsmen he has ever had.
可能是他手下最优秀的年轻桨手
Let's go, Washington!
加油, 华盛顿
Hi, Roger.
嗨, 罗杰
Don't try and do too much. Listen to Moch.
不要想太多做太多 听莫奇的指挥
Stay close, and we'll hope Cal makes a mistake.
跟紧点, 我们希望加州队会犯错
Stay calm with the body.
身体保持冷静
Hold your hands up...
举起手来...
- Inspiring. - Hmm?
- 鼓舞人心 - 嗯？
Uh, you missed the part where I told 'em
呃, 你没听到我告诉他们
just to try not to tip over.
尽量不要翻船的部分
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们
please take your seats.
请就座
Five minutes till the start.
距离比赛开始还有五分钟
Hey, uh, my boys are feeling
嘿, 呃, 我的孩子们感觉
a little under the weather, Al.
有点不舒服, 艾尔
I hope you take it easy on us.
希望你对我们客气点
Not even if I believed you, Ky.
就算我想相信你也不行, 凯
Both teams are in position.
两队都已就位
Winds are out of the north at five miles an hour.
风从北面吹来, 时速五英里
The temperature is a mild 71 degrees.
气温为温和的 71 华氏度
All right, boys. You heard Ulbrickson.
好了 大伙 都听到乌尔布里克森说的了
Stick close and hope they make a mistake.
跟近一点, 希望他们会犯错
That's his way of saying don't embarrass him
他的意思是别让他难堪
'cause that's what he thinks you're gonna do.
因为他认为你们会让他难堪的
I say the hell with all that.
我说都见鬼去吧
All these people didn't just come to see you stick close.
这些人不是来看你们跟近一点的
Let's show Ulbrickson what's in this boat.
我们要让乌尔布里克森看看这艘艇上的都是谁
Ready?
准备好了吗？
The oarsmen are at the ready.
桨手们已经准备就绪
Row! Row!
开始
And they're off!
他们出发了！
Washington is slow off the block.
华盛顿队出发很慢
Step on 'em early! 38!
早点踩 38号!
Let's go! Good.
我们走 很好
Yeah, we got 'em.
我们来了
All right. Give me a nice, easy 28.
好吧 给我一个简单明了的 28 拍
In and through.
破 划
And pull!
拉！
Washington's JV boat
华盛顿的初级艇
is racing for the first time in competition.
首次参加比赛
Cal breaks early. Easy work.
加州队轻松突破. 小菜一碟
Cal has half a boat on Washington.
加州队领先华盛顿队有半条艇
Easy, boys. Nice and easy.
放松 孩子们 慢慢来
Cal jumps out to an early lead.
加州队一举取得领先
Washington is struggling to keep pace.
华盛顿队正在努力跟上步伐
That's right. Just keep them in sight.
这就对了 别让他们离开视线
Don't sky the blade, McMillin!
别让桨片划空, 麦克米伦
In, through.
破 划
Shoulders loose.
肩膀松弛
In the legs!
腿用力
Cal opening up a full boat on Washington.
加州队领先华盛顿队整个船身
And at the quarter mark, it's Cal up a full boat.
在四分之一标志处, 加州队已经领先整个船身
Come on! Come on, Washington!
来吧 加油 华盛顿
We got this, boys! Come on.
我们能行, 孩子们来吧
Through.
划
In, through.
破 划
Don't panic, Bobby.
别慌, 鲍比
Don't rush.
不要着急
Cal still showing no signs of slowing down.
加州队仍然没有放缓的迹象
Washington is getting its first taste of competition.
华盛顿队初尝竞争滋味
Something Coach Ulbrickson can hope to build on.
乌尔布里克森教练还可以再接再厉
Through! In, and through!
划 破 划
Push! Push!
推 推
All right, here we go, boys.
好了, 开始吧, 孩子们
Give me 35.
给我 35 拍
Let's show 'em what we got.
让他们看看我们的厉害吧
Build! Build it!
用力 用力
What are they doing? I said let Cal come back to them.
他们在干什么？我说过让加州队走在前面
Now at the halfway mark.
现在赛程过半
The Huskies with a burst.
哈士奇队突然爆发
Just passing the halfway point and Washington is surging.
刚过半程, 华盛顿队就开始发力
Oh, you better be right, Moch.
哦, 你最好是对的, 莫奇
In, through!
破 划
- In, through! - Here they come.
- 破 划 - 他们来了
Here comes Washington.
华盛顿队来了
Eyes up.
抬头
- Eyes up! - Push!
- 抬头 - 推
They're past the three-quarter mark.
他们已经越过了四分之三标志处
Cal and Washington are neck and neck!
加州队和华盛顿队齐头并进！
Go! Row!
加油 划
Stay loose!
放松！
Push! Push!
推 推
Cal is falling back.
加州队正在落后
Let's go!
冲
Washington is picking up the pace!
华盛顿正在加快节奏！
Washington's passing Cal!
华盛顿队超过加州队
And look at this.
看看这个
The Washington boat has taken the lead!
华盛顿队已经取得领先
Washington by half a boat!
华盛顿队领先半条艇身
- Row! Let's go! - Come on!
- 划！我们走 - 来吧
Two hundred meters to go!
还有两百米！
- Washington is pulling ahead! - Twenty more strokes!
- 华盛顿领先！ - 再划二十桨！
Come on, come on.
加油 加油
Come on! Go!
加油 上
Washington by a full boat!
华盛顿队领先了整条船身
In and through! One hundred meters!
破 划！一百米！
Fifteen more!
还有 15 桨！
Come on! Come on!
加油 加油
Through! Ten more!
蹬！还有十桨
Fifty meters!
五十米！
五十米
Washington is going to do it!
华盛顿队要赢了！
You got this! In and through!
你们能行！破 划
Push!
推！
Twenty-five meters!
二十五米！
And there's the flag!
那就是终点
Washington has done it!
华盛顿队做到了！
Washington's junior boat has won their first competition!
华盛顿队初级艇赢得了他们的首场比赛！
Yeah!
耶
What a promising start for these young men!
对于这些年轻人来说, 这是一个多么有希望的开始！
Jesus!
天啊
I got nine seconds under the course record.
我这比赛道记录快了 9 秒
Same.
一样
And the final third is faster than the first.
最后三分之一的速度比一开始还要快
Where the hell did that come from?
到底是从哪里来的力气？
I guess that little runt knew what he was doin'.
我猜那个小矮子知道自己在做什么
- Yeah! - Yeah!
- 好哦 - 好哦
It's all you, boys!
干的漂亮, 孩子们
All you!
你们都是
Yeah!
漂亮
One!
一
Two!
二
Three!
三
I like your hat. Thank you. Thank you.
我喜欢你的帽子 谢谢
Come on!
来吧
Washington!
华盛顿
Come on!
来吧
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
Hi.
你好
I could get used to this.
我可以习惯这样
How did your first win feel?
第一次获胜的感觉如何？
Great.
好极了
Next one's gonna be even faster.
下一次会更快
How did you go so fast?
你怎么划得这么快？
Oh, we just rowed as quick as we could.
哦, 我们就是拼命在划
It must have been hard, even though you're strong.
虽然你很强壮, 但这一定很难
You get tired?
你累吗？
Yeah, yeah, it was pretty rough.
是啊, 是啊, 是挺艰难的
Too tired to go someplace quiet
太累了, 不想去安静的地方
and show me how you did it?
告诉我你是如何做到的吗？
Oh, hell no.
哦, 当然不会
You know, this might make all the times
你知道, 让莫里斯吐在我背上
Morris puked on my back worth it.
那么多次 可能也都值了
I got this today.
我今天收到了这个
Some fellow in a suit just gave it to me.
是一个西装革履的家伙给我的
Said us winning made him so happy, he wanted me to have...
他说我们赢了让他很高兴, 他想让我...
Shoot, we all made him happy, Gordo.
我们都让他很开心, 戈多
Kid in my algebra class
我代数课上的孩子
offered to do my homework for me.
主动要帮我做作业
- I let the sap do it. - You should.
- 我就让他做了 - 应该的
We keep on winnin',
我们继续赢下去
we're gonna have it made in this place.
可能真的会在这里实现的
- You did so good today. - Huh?
- 你今天干得真不错 - 嗯？
I said you did so...
我说你今天...
I said you did so good today.
我说你今天表现得很好
Thank you.
谢谢
It was... It was fun.
这是...很有趣
What?
什么？
Come here. I said it was fun.
过来 我说这很有趣
Do you wanna go someplace quiet?
你想去个安静的地方吗？
Watcha doin'?
你在干什么？
I'm watching.
我就看看
Why aren't you talking to anybody?
你为什么不跟任何人说话？
I'm not much of a talker.
我不太爱说话
Ah.
啊
Hey, look over there.
嘿, 看那边
You see that beanpole in the glasses?
看到那个戴眼镜的豆芽菜了吗？
Yeah.
是啊
He's studying Latin.
他在学拉丁语
- Oh. - Latin.
- 哦 - 拉丁语
You don't have to say much.
你不必说太多
Listen, Hume.
听着, 休谟
Tonight, not tomorrow night, or next week.
今晚, 不是明晚, 也不是下周
Tonight is your best shot.
今晚是你最好的机会
You go on. I think I'm okay.
你继续 我想我没事
Christ sake.
看在上帝的份上
Hey, listen up!
嘿, 听好了
We got a musician in our midst.
我们中间有一位音乐家
With a little encouragement,
稍加鼓励
we might just get him to give us some live music.
可能会让他给我们带来一些现场音乐
Don Hume!
唐·休姆
Get up here. Get up here.
快上来 快上来
Come on, Don!
来吧, 唐！
No. No.
不 不
- Hey, watch out. - No, no, no, no, no.
- 嘿, 小心点 - 不, 不, 不
Bobby, get the stool.
鲍比, 拿凳子来
The piano man.
钢琴师
John, John, John
约翰, 约翰, 约翰
- No, no, no. - There we go.
- 不, 不, 不 - 到了
All ready for you there, maestro.
一切准备就绪, 大师.
Let's hear it for Don!
让我们为唐鼓掌！
Don Hume.
唐·休姆
Come on, Don!
来吧, 唐！
We know you can do it.
我们知道你能做到
- Come on, Don. - Come on, Donnie.
- 来吧 唐 - 加油 唐尼
I don't think that I should be here.
我觉得我不应该在这
He can't be in here.
他不能进来
Oh, shut up, Carolyn.
闭嘴 卡洛琳
I saw you smoking at your window last week.
上周我看见你在窗前抽烟
It was too loud in there.
那边太吵了
Yeah. People are happy. They're having fun.
对 大家很快乐 他们玩得很开心
Yeah, because of you.
对, 因为你
Okay, I'm changing.
好吧, 我要换衣服了
Eyes on the wall.
眼睛看着墙壁
Right.
好
Did you know you were gonna win?
你知道自己会赢吗？
No. My arms, they were shaking.
不, 我的手臂在颤抖
I was so nervous.
我太紧张了
We were all screaming so loud.
我们都在大声尖叫
The radio said it was the fastest ever.
广播说这是有史以来最快的一次
Yeah, that's what Coach told us.
对, 教练是这么告诉我们的
I bet you win every race.
我打赌你们每场都能赢
Just don't get all stuck-up and everything.
只要不自命不凡就好
I just kept that in case I ever ran into you again.
我把它留着, 以防再遇到你
And had to, um...
不得不...
prove that you had that crush on me, like I said.
证明你暗恋过我, 就像我说的那样
Miss Simdars, open this door.
西姆达斯小姐, 开门
You... You should go.
你...你该走了
You should go. You need to go. You need to go.
你该走了 你必须走了 你必须走了
Miss Simdars, open this door right now, young lady.
西姆达斯小姐, 马上开门, 小姐
If you have a male visitor in there,
如果里面有男性访客
well, you know the consequences.
那么, 你知道后果是什么
One minute!
一分钟
- What? - Is that too far?
- 什么 - 太高了吗？
- No. - You're fine.
- 不 - 那很好
Miss Simdars!
西姆达斯小姐
Ain't we got fun?
我们玩得开心吗？
Tax collector's getting closer
收税员越来越近了
Still, we got fun
尽管如此, 我们还是很开心
There's nothing surer
没有比这更确定的了
The rich get rich and the poor get poorer
富者愈富, 穷者愈穷
In the meantime, in between time
同时, 此时
Ain't we got fun?
我们玩得开心吗？
Well done!
干得好
Okay! Yeah!
好 好
Don Hume, ladies and gentlemen.
唐·休姆, 女士们先生们
- Harvard, Yale? - Mm-hmm.
- 哈佛 耶鲁？- 嗯
Both have put up times we haven't gotten close to.
两队的成绩都是我们无法企及的
That's how it usually goes.
通常就是这样
Kids back East are in boats before they're in shoes.
东部的孩子在会穿鞋之前就已经上艇了
Schools just have more talent to choose from.
学校有更多的人才可供选择
That's what money buys you.
这就是钱能给你买到的
We need an edge, Tom.
我们需要点优势, 汤姆
Through. In and through.
划 破 划
In and through.
破 划
And through!
划
Eyes up!
抬头
In and through!
破 划
Stand tall.
抬高
Legs through.
蹬腿
In and through.
破 划
Legs through.
蹬腿
In, through.
破 划
In and through.
Legs through.
蹬腿
Way-nuff!
停桨
Everybody else tires and they just get stronger.
其他人都累了, 他们却越战越勇
That's the third time they beat the varsity squad.
这是他们第三次击败校队
Maybe next time.
也许下次就输了
I just think it's too big of a risk.
我只是觉得风险太大了
Poughkeepsie is more than just the championship this year.
波基普西今年不仅仅是冠军赛
It's for the Olympics.
也是奥运会选拔赛
I know what the race means, Tom.
我知道比赛意味着什么, 汤姆
Experience counts for something in big races.
在大型比赛中, 经验很重要
Half those guys on varsity
校队有一半人
competed at Poughkeepsie last year.
去年在波基普西参加过比赛
- And they lost. - They're better this year.
- 他们输了 - 他们今年更好
If you didn't know their ages,
如果不知道他们的年龄
you didn't know how long they've been rowing,
不知道他们划了多久
you're looking at both boats for the first time...
假设你第一次看到这两艘艇...
A time trial in the backyard does not count.
后院的计时赛不算
That is not the same thing as a race.
这和正规赛场是两码事
Look at the competition times.
看看比赛时间
It's not that easy.
没那么容易
Come on, you know that.
拜托, 你知道的
Yes. Yes.
是的, 是的
Yes, I know.
是的, 我知道
You're acting like the varsity boat is scrappin'.
你表现得就像校队是群废物一样
You know that boat hasn't lost a race either.
要知道, 那艘艇也没有输过比赛
And it wasn't that long ago
就在不久前
you were just hopin' the JV boat
你还在期待初级队
was gonna make it to the finish line without sinking.
能在不沉没的情况下坚持到终点
Now, Al,
现在, 艾尔
now you're talkin' about putting all our chips on 'em.
现在你却说要把我们所有的筹码都押在他们身上
Do you think varsity could medal in Berlin?
你认为校队能在柏林拿奖吗？
We're not talkin' about a medal.
我们不是在谈论奖牌
We're talkin' about a shot at gettin' there.
我们说的是去那里的机会
If they got there?
就算他们到了那？
I don't know.
我不知道
We need a win this year, Al.
我们今年需要一场胜利, 艾尔
The people who pay us, they need a win.
给我们付钱的人 他们需要一场胜利
You send a boat full of kids down there
你派一艇孩子过去
and they trip up,
他们就会被绊倒
you're sticking your neck way out there.
你就等着
Makes it a real easy target. And mine, too.
引颈就戮吧 我也是
I need this job.
我需要这份工作
What do you think, George?
你怎么看, 乔治？
Hmm.
嗯
When you were in a boat,
你在艇上那会
you rowed like no one else that's ever come through here.
你的划艇技术这里无人能及
I remember watching you,
我记得我看着你
wondering how fast one of my shells could go
真想知道我的船到底能跑多快
if there were eight just like you in it.
如果里面有八个和你一样的人
That bunch of kids
那群孩子
might be as close to that as I'll ever get.
可能是最接近我这想法的了
And if I send them out there and they aren't ready?
如果我把他们派出去, 他们还没准备好呢？
Then it's like Tom said.
那就像汤姆说的那样
The axe will likely fall,
斧头很可能会落下
and fall hard.
砍得脖子疼
Now you're starting to sound like my wife.
现在你的口气开始像我妻子了
Well, Hazel's a smart woman.
海泽尔是个聪明的女人
I'll take that as a compliment.
我就当你在夸我
Good morning, everybody.
大家早上好
Thank you.
谢谢
Now, as we all know, uh, the Poughkeepsie Regatta
众所周知, 波基普西帆艇赛
is always the most important race of the season.
一直是本赛季最重要的比赛
This year, there's even more riding on it,
今年, 它的意义更加重大
because the winner will qualify for an Olympic spot.
因为获胜者将获得奥运会的参赛资格
Yes!
好
It's also a race that the University of Washington
它也是华盛顿大学已近二十年
has not won in almost two decades,
未尝胜绩的一个赛事
but... but...
但是...
we have a boat this year
我们今年有一艘艇
that I believe could change all that.
我相信他们可以改变这一切
A boat that could not only win at Poughkeepsie,
这艘艇不仅能在波基普西夺冠
but
而且
is strong enough to have a real shot in Berlin.
有足够的实力在柏林一展身手
And, uh...
还有...
that boat is our junior boat.
那艘艇就是我们的初级艇
Yeah, you heard me.
是的, 你们都听到了
Listen, I understand that that's unorthodox.
听着, 我知道这不合常理
- Unorthodox? It's insane. - I'm doing everything I can...
- 不合常理？简直是疯了 - 我正在尽我所能...
You can't do that.
你不能这么做
in the best interests of our team
我们团队和华盛顿大学的
and the University of Washington.
最佳利益
Thank you.
谢谢
This is bullshit!
这简直是胡扯！
Have you lost your mind?
你疯了吗？
What about those boys who spent
那些花了四年时间
the last four years working for this?
在这上面的孩子怎么办？
My job is to put the best boat in the water, Ben.
我的工作就是派最好的艇去参赛, 本
Your job? I pay for your job.
你的工作？我付的钱
Without the boosters, where do you think
没有我支持, 你认为
the money for your boats comes from, huh?
你们买艇的钱是从哪里来的？
For your goddamn salary?
你那该死的薪水哪里来
How about you let me do my job?
让我做我的工作怎么样？
Let's just settle down
让我们安定下来
and talk about this calmly. Come on.
冷静地谈谈 来吧
There's nothin' to talk about, Jay.
没什么好谈的 杰伊
My team, my decision.
我的团队, 我做主
Then it's not your team anymore.
那就不再是你的团队了
I'll make sure your ass is fired
我会让你屁股挪窝
before the train leaves for Poughkeepsie.
在火车开往波基普西之前
- Ben, we're not gonna get... - All right.
- 本, 我们不会搞到... - 好吧
Bolles is just as capable as you.
博勒斯和你一样能干
Better even.
甚至更好
I'd do the same as Al.
我会和艾尔一样选择
I hope you know what you're doing.
我希望你知道自己在做什么
Ben!
本
Do I?
我知道吗？
Sure you do.
你当然知道
I can't believe you're going to the Olympics.
真不敢相信你要去参加奥运会
We gotta beat those other schools first,
我们得先打败其他学校
but Coach says we have as good a shot as anybody.
但教练说, 我们的机会和其他队一样多
You can't flirt with any of those New York girls.
你不准和那些纽约女孩调情
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Be back in a second.
马上回来
Joe?
乔？
Saw your picture in the paper.
在报纸上看到你的照片了
Harry Junior clipped it out.
小哈利把它剪了下来
When did you get back from California?
你们什么时候从加州回来的？
Couple of years.
好几年了
You know, things weren't much better down there.
那里的情况也没好到哪里去
So, you've been here all that time?
这么说, 你一直都在这里？
Down the road a bit.
就在前面一点点远
Were you ever gonna tell me?
你打算告诉我吗？
You're doin' all right.
你做得很好
I was 14 when you left.
你离开的时候, 我才 14 岁
I went to war when I was that age.
我在那个年纪就上战场了
So, what do you wanna do, Joe?
那么, 你在想什么, 乔？
Huh?
啊？
Move home?
想搬回家吗？
I mean, I could use the help.
我是说, 我需要人帮忙
Tell you what, I'll pay you a dollar a day
这样吧, 我每天付你一美元
if you still remember how to cut a tree.
如果你还记得如何砍树的话
Or maybe you'd rather just keep rowing your boat.
或者, 你宁愿继续划你的艇
You don't owe me a thing, Joe.
你不欠我什么 乔
I don't owe you.
我也不欠你的
You're doing just fine.
你做得很好
I'll pass on regards.
我会转达问候的
I'm sorry.
对不起
Works out for the best.
这结果是最好的
Yeah, but that doesn't make it okay.
是的, 但这并不意味着就没事了
Maybe.
也许吧
I gotta go.
我得走了
You should come get some sleep
你应该来睡一觉
before the sun rises over that.
在太阳升起之前
I'll be in there soon.
我很快就过去
I sure love that view.
我真喜欢这样的景色
I know.
我知道
I just wish I could enjoy it the way I used to.
我只是希望我能像以前那样享受它
Why don't you
为什么不能
come see if there's another view you can enjoy?
要来看看有没有其他风景可以欣赏吗？
Okay.
好吧
Thank you.
谢谢
We're gonna be the fastest crew the world has ever seen.
我们会成为世界上最快的艇员
Bring home the championship, Al!
把冠军带回家, 艾尔
- And a gold medal! - We'll try.
- 还有一枚金牌 - 我们会努力的
Oh, boy.
哦, 天哪
We might wanna try and win this thing, huh?
我们可能想赢得比赛, 对吧？
No pressure.
没有压力
- Good luck! - Bring it home, boys!
- 祝你们好运 - 把奖牌带回家, 孩子们
I'll be listening on the radio.
我会通过收音机收听
Say hello if they interview you.
如果他们采访你, 跟我问个好
This might be a good time to tell you
现在也许是个好机会
that I'm in love with you, Joe.
告诉你我爱上你了 乔
All right. I gotta go.
好, 我得走了
Hey! Hey!
嘿！
Yeah, she looked at me.
是的, 她看着我
Rantz!
兰茨
I'm busted. Someone give me a penny.
我破产了 谁给我一便士
Lucky, I'll let you watch.
幸运, 我会让你看看的
Hey, Joe, give me your jacket.
嘿, 乔, 把你的夹克给我
That'll get me halfway to ante.
这样我有一半押注的钱了
Joe, stick around.
乔, 别走
Hey, don't run away, Hobo Joe.
嘿, 别走啊, 流浪汉乔
He's playin'.
他开玩笑的
He's playin'. He's playin'.
他开玩笑的 他开玩笑的
He's playin'.
他开玩笑的
- Jesus, Chuck. - Was just jokin'.
- 天啊, 查克 - 开个玩笑而已
Yeah, well, your jokes are lousy.
好吧, 你的笑话太烂了
I didn't mean anything by it.
我没有别的意思
Truth is, my old man went bust years ago, so...
事实是, 我老爸几年前就破产了, 所以...
Any new clothes I wear, I swipe from Woolworth's.
我穿的新衣服, 都是从伍尔沃斯超市顺来的
Doesn't matter.
无所谓
Just sayin' we're not different.
我只是说, 我们并没有什么不同
You and me.
你和我
Except you're not a thief.
只不过你不是小偷
One! Way-nuff!
一 停桨
Drop it.
放下
Again! Need to get sharper.
再来一次！节奏再快一点
Come on.
来吧
You guys are out of sync. Find Hume.
你们不同步 跟着休姆
Take it off Hume.
跟着休姆的节奏
Look like a team, fellas.
像个团队, 伙计们
As one.
同步
You're out of sync.
你们不同步
Okay, no, no. Way-nuff.
好吧 不 停桨
Where are we off? Hey, Joe, you with us?
我们要去哪里？嘿, 乔, 你和我们在一起吗？
- Me? - Yeah, lock in on Don.
- 我 - 对 锁定唐的节奏
What are you talkin' about? I'm not the problem.
你在说什么？我不是问题所在
Go again.
再来一次
Come on.
来吧
In and through.
破 划
All right, give me three more. Three,
好吧, 再来三桨 三
two,
二
one. Way-nuff!
一 停桨
That'd get us a solid sixth.
这样我们肯定能拿到第六名
It's new water, they're still getting comfortable.
这是新水域, 他们还没适应
First times were faster.
第一轮还比较快
They're getting less comfortable.
他们越来越不协调了
What is the matter?
怎么回事？
Not in tune yet. I'll get 'em there, Coach.
还没协调好 我会带好他们的 教练
Let's do it before the race, Bobby.
让我们在赛前先协调好吧 鲍比
Go again.
再来一次
All right, fellas. Port side, back it down.
好了 伙计们 左舷 退后
Starboard, tap on. Ready?
右舷 打开 准备好了吗？
Probably nervous.
可能是紧张
They're just kids, Al.
他们只是孩子, 艾尔
That's why everybody told me
这就是为什么大家都告诉我
I was wrong for bringin' them.
我不该带他们来
I just can't afford for them to be kids.
我没有本钱再让他们孩子气下去了
Not anymore.
现在不一样了
- It looks like they... - I know what's wrong.
- 看起来他们... - 我知道问题在哪了
Bring it in.
带进来
You have 500 perfect meters.
你们完美地划了五百米
And then another five, where it looks like
然后另外五百米, 看起来就像
you're rowing eight different boats.
你们在划八条不同的艇
The timing's just a little off.
时间就是有点对不上
Joe, where is your head at, son?
乔, 你的心思在哪里呢, 孩子？
- It's in the boat. - No, it's not.
- 在艇上 - 不, 不在
You're setting your own pace.
你在跟着自己的节奏走
Your catch is higher than the rest.
你的入水高于其他人
- I'm trying to... - Don't interrupt me.
- 我想...- 别打断我
You're rowing like you're in a single.
你就像在单人划艇一样
We've been doing this too goddamn long to forget
我们已经训练太久了, 不可能忘记
you're in an eight-man shell.
你是在一个八人艇上
Now, do you wanna be in the boat
现在, 你想在艇上吗？
or am I'm gonna put someone else in your seat?
还是我让别人来坐你的位子？
I don't care.
我不在乎
Coy!
科伊
You're in Rantz's seat.
你坐在兰茨的位置上
Get out. You don't care? Get out.
滚出去 你不在乎？滚出去
Coy, come on, let's go.
科伊, 来吧, 我们走
Looks like you're racin' tomorrow.
看来你明天要参加比赛了
Now, maybe we can row as a team.
现在, 也许我们可以像一个团队一样划了
And just go talk to Coach, tell him you want back in.
去和教练谈谈 告诉他你想回去
I'm not beggin' him to give my place back.
我不会求他把我的位置还给我的
- I'm done with that. - Where you gonna go?
- 我受够了 - 你要去哪儿？
Ain't like you got money enough for a train ticket.
你的钱又不够买张火车票
I'll figure somethin' out. I always have.
我会想办法的 我一向如此
Are you gonna live in a car in Poughkeepsie?
你要在波基普西找个车住进去吗？
Hello, Roger. Hello, Joe.
你好 罗杰 你好 乔
I need to put another coat on the Husky Clipper.
我需要在 "赫斯基快艇" 上再涂一层漆
I could use a hand.
需要人帮忙
My grandfather would let me help oil the shells he built.
我爷爷会让我帮他造的船上油
Most hate it because of the smell.
大多数人讨厌它是因为有味道
I catch the scent of whale oil and immediately hear his voice
我一闻到鲸油的味道, 立刻就听到了他的声音
telling me to, "Keep putting it on"
告诉我 "继续涂"
"until you can see your freckles in the reflection."
"直到你能从反光中看到你脸上的雀斑"
That's how I'd know it was good and slick.
这样我才知道它又好又滑
So it would cut through the water like a knife blade.
这样, 它就能像刀刃一样划过水面
How it didn't matter how fast someone rowed
划得再快也没用
if the water didn't flow across the hull
如果水不是以完全正确的方式
in the exact right way.
流过船体
If the weight wasn't balanced just right.
如果重量没有恰到好处地平衡
Every piece working with the other.
每一部分都要相互配合
It's the same with the crew.
艇员也是一样
So much that there's really no difference between the two.
以至于两者之间真的没有什么区别
They're connected by all the hours spent together.
他们因一起度过的所有时光而团结在一起
Sweat and pain
汗水和痛苦
bleeds into the grain as they become one magical thing
洇湿了艇身的纹理, 它们变成了在水面上穿梭的
that moves across the water
一个神奇的东西
like it was born to be nowhere else.
就像天生就不属于任何地方一样
I've built a lot of good boats, but the best ones,
我造过很多好船，但最好的艇
the boats where every part fits exactly as it should,
每一个部件都完全吻合的艇
where every man trusts the one behind him,
每一个人都信任他身后的人的艇
they are the boats people remember forever.
才是人们永远铭记的艇
That's what this boat could be.
这就是这艘艇可能成为的样子
Be a shame for anyone to miss
看看这艘所有部件都完美配合的艇能跑多快
seeing how fast it could go with all the right pieces.
如果有人错过了 那就太可惜了
Joe, your dad gave up on you. He quit on you.
乔 你爸爸放弃了你 他放弃了你
All you know is quitting.
你就只会放弃
But it seems to me you're not him.
但在我看来, 你不是他
Or are you?
或者你是？
- Yes. - Yes, it's very nice.
- 是的 - 是的, 非常好
If I can get you two to just stand together.
如果你们两个能站在一起的话
Just for one. And perfect.
再来一张 完美
I'll, uh, see you over there.
我们那边见
What can I do for you, Joe?
我能为你做什么, 乔？
I want my seat back.
我想要回我的位置
Why?
为什么？
All that time I spent in it,
我在里面度过的那些时光
the work we all did together...
我们一起付出的努力
That boat...
那艘艇...
it's all I got.
是我的全部
The boys and...
伙计们和...
It's all I got.
我只有这些了
I can't lose that.
我不能失去
You know, one of the first things I said to you boys was
我对你们说的第一件事就是
there's no shame if your body can't hold up to this.
如果你的身体承受不了, 这并不丢人
The same goes for the mind.
精神也是一样
Listen, I know it isn't easy to trust every other person
听着, 我知道要信任那条艇上的每一个人
on that boat as much as you trust yourself.
就像信任自己一样 并不容易
But it's not about you.
但这与你无关
As good as you are, it's not about you, Joe,
虽然你很优秀 但这不是你一个人的事情 乔
or me, or anybody else.
或者我, 或其他任何一个人
It's about the boat.
这是关于艇的
Yes, sir.
是的, 先生
It's where I wanna be.
这是我想去的地方
Okay.
好的
Well, you better get dressed.
你最好穿上队服
Thank you.
谢谢
Really, thank you.
真的, 谢谢你
Today's regatta
今天的帆艇赛
is as much a social experiment as it is a race.
它既是一场比赛, 也是一场社会实验
A clash of character.
一场富有精英
Of old money versus no money at all.
和平头百姓的角色冲突
Six boats of want-to's against one filled with have-to's.
六艘生活之艇对上一艘生存之艇
These nine working-class boys arrived from the American West
这九个工人阶级男孩从美国西部来到这里
on the shoulders of a country that sees itself
肩负着一个国家的重任 这个国家从他们
in their determined young faces.
坚定的年轻面孔中看到了自己
Sees their struggles, their grit, their spirit.
看到他们的奋斗 勇气和精神
And they've claimed the Husky Clipper as their own.
他们将 "赫斯基快艇号" 视作自身
Because it's a boat full of underdogs
因为艇上都是弱者
representing an underdog nation.
代表一个弱势民族
A nation of people who have been beaten down
一个被打倒
but refuse to go away.
但拒绝离开的民族
Refuse to stop working hard, 'cause that's all they know.
拒绝停止努力工作, 因为他们只知道努力工作
All they have ever done.
只会努力工作
So, find your place, by the river or the radio.
所以, 找好你的位置, 在河边或收音机旁
And cheer for guts and heart and brawn
今天，我们要为勇气、心智和体力喝彩
to beat privilege and prestige to the finish line today.
战胜特权和名望, 冲向终点
Cheer for the boys from Washington.
为来自华盛顿的小伙子们欢呼
Listen up. We're in lane seven.
听好了 我们在第七道
Navy and Cal are gonna wanna jump to a lead.
海军和加州大学想一举领先
We just let 'em.
就让他们去
This is it, boys.
就是这样, 孩子们
Nice, strong start.
不错的强势开局
We're gonna keep a 42 count coming out, right?
我们要保持 42 拍的速度, 对吧？
California's gonna go out hard, okay?
加利福尼亚队会很拼命的, 好吗？
You gotta stick with them.
你们必须咬死他们
As long as you're within two lengths,
只要你们在两个长度范围以内
- stay under a 30 stroke. - How's your shoulder?
- 就保持在 30 拍 - 你的肩膀怎么样了？
- Are you okay? - I'm good.
- 你还好吗？- 我很好
I wanna see you push yourself through that pain.
我想看到你们坚持到底 战胜痛苦
Then go to a 35 at the halfway mark.
然后在中点换成 35 拍
You're gonna slow down and ease into a nice, steady 34.
你要放慢速度, 慢慢进入平稳的 34 拍
Keep going, keep pushing.
继续前进, 继续推进
Keep pushing all the way through.
坚持到底
All the boats out in front will start to tire
前面的所有艇只都会开始疲劳
and you'll just be getting started.
而你才刚刚开始发力
You know the plan.
都知道计划了
We'll save something for the end.
我们会把一些精力留到最后
Four miles in a boat should be nothing to you.
划艇四英里对你们来说不算什么
This is your race, all right?
这是你们的比赛, 好吗？
This is our time.
这是我们的表演时间
We know what we're doin'. We've been here before, boys.
我们知道自己在做什么 我们以前来过这里
Now better get out there and show 'em what I already know.
现在最好去那边, 展示一下我们的实力
The Poughkeepsie Regatta.
波基普西帆艇赛
Today's regatta is the greatest
今天的帆艇赛是美国最大的
one-day rowing event in America.
单日赛艇比赛
- Watch your step. - Coaches like Ky Ebright,
- 注意脚下 - 像凯·埃布莱特这样的教练,
Rusty Callow and Al Ulbrickson
罗斯特·卡洛和阿尔·乌尔布里克松
are not only hoping for a win,
不仅希望获胜,
but a chance to compete in Berlin.
也想获得去柏林参赛的机会
As rowing fans board observation cars
赛艇爱好者们登上观景台
and crowd the shores of the Hudson River,
挤满哈德逊河岸,
seven shells take their places at the starting line.
七艘赛艇在起跑线上已就位
Syracuse, Navy,
锡拉丘兹大学, 海军,
Cornell, and Columbia,
康奈尔大学和哥伦比亚大学
Penn, Cal, and Washington ready themselves
宾夕法尼亚大学 加州大学和华盛顿大学在为
for what could be the most important race
可能是他们年轻的生命中
of their young lives.
最重要的比赛做准备
A chance to compete in the Olympics.
一个参加奥运会的机会
Let's go.
我们走吧
- Good luck, Jack. - You, too.
- 祝你好运 杰克 - 你也是
The starting gun is up.
发令枪已举起
Oars to frontstops.
桨在前方已就位
Nearly 100,000 spectators hold their breath in anticipation.
近 10 万名观众屏住呼吸, 翘首以盼
A hush falling over Crum Elbow.
克鲁姆埃尔伯水面一片寂静
- Row! And here we go.
- 划！开始了
Washington Huskies are now rowing
华盛顿哈士奇队正在划艇
against the seniors of Cal.
对抗加州大学的学长们
Huskies are the only junior boat in the competition.
"哈士奇" 是比赛中唯一的初级艇
Give me a nice, easy 28.
给我一个简单明了的 28 拍
Fall in with Don.
跟着唐的节拍
In and through.
破 划
These seven finely trained crews
这七支训练有素的艇员队伍
are churning the waters of the Upper Hudson
正在搅动上哈德逊河的水域
in a supreme rowing test
在一场力量、速度和协调性的
of power, speed and coordination.
的最高测试中
Hold that pace, Bobby.
保持节拍, 鲍比
And at the quarter mark, we have California, Penn
在第一阶段, 加利福尼亚州 宾夕法尼亚州
and Navy out in front
和海军冲在前面
with a half-boat lead on the rest of the field.
领先其他队半条艇位
All right, your stroke rate is perfect.
好了, 你们划得节奏非常好
Save your power.
节约能量
Let 'em get tired.
让他们累去
Wear 'em down.
损耗他们
Washington is falling back to last place.
华盛顿正在跌到最后一名
Four lengths behind the leaders.
落后领先者四个艇长
Now, Bobby.
现在 鲍比
Save!
节约
Save power.
节约能量
Wear 'em down.
损耗他们
- What's he doing? - It has to be now.
- 他在干什么？- 不能再等了
Come on, boys.
来吧, 孩子们
Wait for it.
等着
All right, Don, give me 36. Go!
好了 唐 给我 36 拍 开始
Legs through.
蹬腿
And here they come.
他们来了
Looking for freshwater,
看看新手
Bobby Moch is steering right into Syracuse's lane.
鲍比·莫奇正在赶上锡拉丘兹队
In and through. Let's go.
破 划 我们走
Legs up.
抬腿
Jab! Jab!
戳！戳！
Get off us!
放过我们
Hey, go to hell, Syracuse!
嘿, 去死吧, 锡拉库扎！
What the hell is that?
那是什么鬼？
Washington is passing Syracuse.
华盛顿正在超越锡拉丘兹大学
And with a mile and a half behind them,
他们身后还有一英里半的距离
teams are falling away
各队七零八落
but no one is gaining on California and Navy.
但加州大学队和海军队无人能望其项背
Attaboy.
好样的
Row! Row!
摇 摇
Holding a four-length lead,
保持四个艇长的领先优势
Cal and Navy are in a two-boat race.
加州大学和海军正在进行双艇竞赛
All right, give me 10 big ones for Ulbrickson. Go!
好吧, 给我十个大的给乌尔布里克森看看 冲
Washington has picked up the pace.
华盛顿加快了步伐
Bobby Moch finally getting his crew in this race.
鲍比·莫奇终于让他的队员冲进了比赛
The Huskies sweeping by Cornell.
哈士奇队横扫康奈尔队
Headed for Penn and Columbia.
追向宾夕法尼亚州立大学和哥伦比亚大学
Navy and Cal still ahead by four lengths.
海军和加州大学仍然领先四个身位
All right! Give me 40!
好吧 给我 40 拍
Let's go!
上啊
In, through!
破 划
Washington is quickly gaining on Columbia's Lions.
华盛顿正在迅速超越哥伦比亚雄狮
Better not be too late.
最好还不算太晚
The Husky Clipper bustles by Columbia...
赫斯基快艇超过了哥伦比亚...
- Come on!  - ...and into third place!
- 来吧 -...上升到了第三位
Come on!
来吧
Push! Extend!
推 展
Now, give me 10 more
现在, 再来 10 桨
for Pocock!
为了波克
With 400 meters to go, here comes Washington!
还剩 400 米, 华盛顿赶上来了
In and through!
破 划
In, through!
- Through! - Twenty more strokes!
- 划！- 再来 20 桨
Nineteen!
19！
Washington has taken second place!
华盛顿来到了第二位
Do they have enough left to catch Cal?
他们还有足够的时间追上加州大学队吗？
Legs through!
蹬腿
- Come on, boys. - Come on.
- 来吧, 孩子们 - 来吧
You got this, boys.
你们能行的, 孩子们
Look at Washington!
看看华盛顿吧！
I don't believe what I'm seeing.
真不敢相信我所看到的
Can the Huskies do it? Can they do it?
哈士奇队能做到吗？他们能做到吗？
Give me 10 big ones
来 10 个大的
for all the people who didn't believe in you!
给所有不相信你的人！
Go!
冲
Give me Cal!
给我拿下加州队！
I want Cal!
拿下加州队
Yeah, we're workin'! Whoo!
对 我们要赢了 喔
They're making their move!
他们正在前进
Boys, come on.
孩子们, 加油
Legs through!
蹬腿！
With 200 meters left,
还剩 200 米
Washington is passing Cal!
华盛顿正在超越加州
In, through!
破 划
Eyes up!
抬头
With 100 meters to go, Washington is going to do it!
还有 100 米, 华盛顿就要赢了！
Washington is going to do it!
华盛顿要赢了
Through! In and through!
划 破 划
- Eyes up! In! - Come on.
- 抬头 破 - 来吧
Washington has won the race, folks!
华盛顿赢得了比赛, 各位！
Washington has won the race!
华盛顿赢得了比赛！
Washington has won!
华盛顿赢了！
What a race!
多么精彩的比赛
Coach Ulbrickson's big gamble has paid off,
教练乌尔布里克森的豪赌得到了回报
ladies and gentlemen.
女士们, 先生们
The Washington Huskies
华盛顿哈士奇队
are going to Berlin to compete for gold.
要去柏林争夺金牌了
- What a race indeed! - Yes!
- 真是一场精彩的比赛 - 是的！
Oh...
哦...
I do love your smile.
我真的很喜欢你的笑容
You should do it more often.
你应该经常笑一笑
We did it, boys!
我们成功了, 孩子们！
I think that you were trying to give us all a heart attack.
我觉得你是想让我们都得心脏病
I just didn't want to break their rhythm till I had to.
不到万不得已, 我不想打破他们的节奏
I honest to God didn't know
我真的不知道
there were this many shrimp in the entire world.
全世界有这么多的虾
Do you mind sharing with our listeners,
您是否介意与我们的听众分享一下
what was the feeling in the boat
在艇上的感觉如何
when you were four lengths back?
在你们落后四个艇位的时候？
Was there any panic?
有没有恐慌？
Uh, there was no panic.
没有恐慌
All of us,
我们所有人
we knew we could make up the ground when we needed to.
我们都知道我们可以在需要的时候到位
And, if I could,
如果可以的话
could I say hello to my girl Joyce back home?
我能跟我的乔伊斯打个招呼吗？
I'll let you wear the gold medal when I get back.
等我回来就让你戴上金牌
That's right, folks.
没错, 各位
They'll be bringing the gold medal home
他们将把金牌带回家
for all of us back in Washington.
为了我们所有华盛顿人
Oh.
哦
This is great.
这太棒了
So, you guys all knew about it when?
你们是什么时候知道的？
And I'm hearing about it tonight?
我今晚才听到？
You know what this sounds like to me?
你知道这听起来像什么吗？
It sounds like you guys are changing the rules
听起来你们好像在改变规则
because you're trying to steal this from us.
因为你想从我们这里偷走这个
No one is trying to steal anything, Coach Ulbrickson.
没有人想偷什么 乌尔布里克森教练
I'm just speaking to you
我只是和你谈谈
as the U.S. Rowing Olympic Chairman
以美国赛艇奥林匹克主席的身份
and telling you the facts.
告诉你这个事实
U.S. Rowing does not have the money
美国赛艇协会没有钱
to fund your trip to Berlin.
来资助您的柏林之旅
And how is that even possible?
这怎么可能呢？
It's not just rowing.
不仅仅是划艇
Swimming, fencing.
游泳 击剑
There are many other sports that are dealing with...
还有许多其他体育运动也在面对...
Exactly how much are we supposed to come up with?
我们到底需要出多少钱？
- $5,000. - Five?
- 五千美金 - 五千？
- In a week? - In a week.
- 一周内？ - 一周内
And what if we can't come up with it?
如果我们拿不出来呢？
Well, the committee would have to find
委员会不得不去找
a suitable replacement to compete in Berlin.
合适的接替者去柏林比赛
Suitable like who, Henry? Like your Penn squad?
谁合适, 亨利？像你的宾大队？
If necessary, yes.
如果有必要, 可以
We'd of course give California the first opportunity.
我们当然首先会给加州队一个机会
Either team is a better option
无论派哪支队去
than not sending a team at all.
总比不派队好
This is bullshit, Henry. It's bullshit.
这是废话 亨利 都是胡扯
You didn't expect us to win, and we won.
你没想到我们会赢, 但我们赢了
Yeah, you couldn't win on the water. None of you.
是啊, 你们不可能在水上赢我们 你们谁也赢不了
I don't like this situation.
我不喜欢这种情况
- Now, you're makin' up the rules. - Bullshit.
- 现在, 你在胡编乱造 - 胡说八道
I don't like the situation
我也不喜欢这种情况
- any more than you do. - Yeah, sure you don't.
- 和你一样 - 你当然不喜欢
- Bullshit. - We'll figure this out.
- 胡说八道 - 我们会解决的
How are we supposed to come up with $5,000?
我们怎么能拿出 5000 美元呢？
Our university will reach out to alumni and boosters.
我们大学将与校友和支持者联系
See if they can scrape anything up.
看看他们能不能支持一点
And if they can't find enough?
如果他们的资助也不够呢？
Then it'd be Cal
那就会是加州大学队
or Penn.
或宾州大学队去了
We beat those guys.
我们打败了那些家伙
I know.
我知道
No way we let those rich pricks go instead of us.
我们绝不能让那些有钱的混蛋代替我们去
Then we better find some money.
那我们最好找点钱出来
Yeah.
是啊
Al, where you goin'?
艾尔, 你去哪儿？
Help send the Huskies to Berlin.
帮助将哈士奇队送往柏林
Thank you. You have a nice day.
谢谢 祝您愉快
- Thank you, sir. - Sure.
- 谢谢 - 好的
Hey, guys.
嘿, 伙计们
The Olympic rowing team needs your help to get to Berlin.
奥运赛艇队需要您的帮助才能到达柏林
We only got a couple days left.
我们只剩下几天时间了
Fellas, I got a dollar.
伙计们, 我有一块钱
Spare a couple dollars. Help us beat the Germans.
捐助几块钱 帮助我们打败德国人
All right.
好的
Thanks. My name's Roger.
谢谢 我叫罗杰
Hey, I'm Chuck.
嘿, 我是查克
Oh, please.
哦, 拜托
Well, you're running out of days, Coach.
好吧, 你的时间不多了, 教练
- You have what, four left? - Three.
- 你还缺多少, 四千？- 三千
And we've only gotten halfway
我们的资金才募集到了
to what the Olympic Committee says we need.
奥委会说的一半
So, if you don't raise the money,
所以, 如果你筹不足钱
you go back to Seattle
你们就得回西雅图去
while some other team goes to Berlin?
与此同时, 其他队会去柏林？
Correct. And that goes against
正确 这有悖于
everything sports should be about.
一切体育精神
Athletes should be rewarded for performance.
运动员应该因为表现而得到奖励
No politics,
不搞政治
no adjusted scoring or selection
不搞加分 或者
based on wealth and standing.
基于财富和地位来选人
May the best man win.
让最优秀的人获胜
That's what they say. That's what it should be.
他们是这么说的 就应该是这样
These boys, Washington's boys,
这些孩子 华盛顿的孩子
this country's boys,
这个国家的孩子
my boys,
我的孩子
they have proven themselves to be the best.
他们已经证明了自己是最棒的
Help us send the Huskies to Berlin.
帮助我们将哈士奇队送往柏林
A reminder, folks, every little bit helps.
提醒各位, 一点一滴都是帮助
Thank you so much.
非常感谢
Come on, support our boys.
来吧, 支持我们的孩子
All right. Thank you so much.
好的 非常感谢
Thank you so much.
非常感谢
Thank you so much. Thank you.
非常感谢 谢谢
We got $92 from Tacoma in honor of Roger Morris.
我们从塔科马募集了 92 美元, 以罗杰·莫里斯之名
$75 more from Sequim for Joe Rantz.
再加上从塞奎姆给乔·兰茨募集的 75 美元
$90 from Olympia for Don Hume.
从奥林匹亚给唐·休姆募集的 90 美元
Every hometown of these boys has given somethin'.
每个孩子的家乡都付出了努力
Pacific Telegraph just sent $250 this evening.
太平洋电报公司今晚刚寄来 250 美元
Where does that put us
我们一共筹集了
with everything else we've got?
多少了现在？
- Eh, close. - But?
- 嗯, 差不多了 - 但是呢？
Well, close is just close, Al.
好吧, 接近就是接近, 艾尔
And we're out of time.
我们没时间了
Come on.
来吧
Mrs. Ulbrickson, I'm looking for your husband.
乌尔布里克森太太 我来找你丈夫
We still got four hours, Ky.
我们还有四个小时呢 凯
Racing the clock as usual.
像往常一样争分夺秒
I can't lie to you, Al.
我不能骗你, 艾尔
My boys would love to go to Berlin.
我的孩子们很想去柏林
How short are you?
你还缺多少？
$300.
300美金
Give or take.
左右
Hmm.
嗯
May I?
可以吗？
This is from the Cal Bears.
这是来自加州熊队的
An IOU for $300.
一张 300 美元的欠条
Give or take.
或多或少
Ky.
凯
No one deserves to go but your boys.
除了你的孩子们, 没有人有资格去
Gentlemen.
先生们
Mrs. Ulbrickson.
乌尔布里克森夫人
And if there's any extra, you can bring me back a souvenir.
如果钱还有剩的话, 你们可以给我带点纪念品回来
Aboard the SS Manhattan,
登上 SS 曼哈顿号
a shipload of American athletes sails for Hamburg.
一船美国运动员驶往汉堡
The Olympic Games, their goal.
奥林匹克运动会, 他们的目标
Here is Jesse Owens,
这是杰西·欧文斯,
the one-man track team from the University of Ohio.
俄亥俄大学的一个人组成的田径队
Some say, "The greatest ever."
有人说是, "有史以来最伟大的"
More than 300 athletes will march ashore
300 多名运动员将上岸
on German soil, ready to fight for gold.
在德国的土地上, 准备为金牌而战
Among the participants are the University of Washington's
参与者包括华盛顿大学的
junior varsity eight-man rowing crew.
八人赛艇初级队
The boat is ready to do battle
这艘小艇已经准备好
with the likes of Italy, Great Britain
与意大利、英国
and Germany,
和德国等
all favorites in this most grueling of events.
最受欢迎的队伍一决高下
In Berlin, the preparations for the Games are complete,
在柏林, 奥运会的筹备工作已经完成
and the German people are ready to welcome
德国人民已经准备好欢迎
athletes from 52 countries.
来自 52 个国家的运动员
German Chancellor Adolf Hitler
德国总理阿道夫·希特勒
has promised a spectacle like no other,
曾承诺要举办一场无与伦比的盛会,
and plans to attend a variety of events.
并计划出席各种活动
In Hamburg, thousands of cheering Germans
在汉堡, 成千上万的德国人欢呼雀跃
welcome the Americans as they ready to disembark.
欢迎准备上岸的美国人
These amateur athletes
这些业余运动员
have sacrificed so much to represent their country,
他们为代表自己的国家做出了巨大牺牲
and as the opening of the Games is just days away,
还有几天奥运会就要开幕了
Americans at home and abroad
海内外的美国人
look forward to rooting for these dedicated athletes.
期待为这些敬业的运动员们加油助威
Hi.
你好
All right.
好的
Get changed, we'll go look over the course.
换好衣服, 我们去看看航道
This is great.
这太棒了
Not bad.
还不错
- This'll do. - It's better than back home.
- 这就够了 - 比在老家强多了
Heil Hitler.
希特勒万岁
Remember the Alamo.
记住阿拉莫
Joe, opening ceremony.
乔, 开幕式
Come on, you're gonna be late.
快点 你要迟到了
I think I gotta skip.
我想我就不去了
I'm just too tired.
我太累了
Why, what's the problem, Don?
怎么了, 有什么问题吗, 唐？
Don doesn't feel so great.
唐感觉不太好
Go join the rest. I'll, uh... I'll stay.
去和其他人会合吧 我留下
I'll hang back. You need to walk with your team.
我来殿后 你得和你的团队一起走
Thanks, George.
谢谢你, 乔治
All right, get some rest.
好了, 休息吧
Try and eat somethin'.
吃点东西吧
Ungarn.
匈牙利
You're Jesse, right? Jesse Owens?
你是杰西, 对吧？杰西·欧文斯？
I am.
我是
You really the fastest man in the world?
你真的是世界上跑得最快的人吗？
- I don't know. - Folks around here say
- 我不知道 - 这里的人说
you're gonna win every race you're in.
你会赢下你参加的每一场比赛
Well, I hope so.
但愿如此
Show those Germans what for, all right?
给德国人点厉害瞧瞧, 好吗？
- No. - No?
- 不 - 不
Not the Germans.
不是给德国人
The folks back home.
是给家乡的父老乡亲的
United States of America.
美利坚合众国
The Hungarian team
匈牙利队
offering their respect to the German leader.
向德国领导人表示敬意
And here come the Americans.
美国人来了
With no salute from the United States.
美国没有敬礼
Sounds like the boys are making friends.
听起来孩子们正在交朋友
All right, the winds are up.
好了, 起风了
That's good for us. You're protected in lane two.
这对我们有好处 你们在第二道不受直接影响
Let all the other boats farther out
让其他更远的船
deal with the gusts.
去对付阵风吧
Bobby, the tighter you hold the line,
鲍比, 你越是紧守
the smoother the ride.
比赛就越平稳
Now, three prelims.
现在是三场预赛
The winner of each gets an automatic berth in the finals.
每场预赛的获胜者将自动获得总决赛的入场券
That is what you want. You want a day off
这就是你们想要的 休息一天
and let the other teams wear themselves out
让其他球队疲于奔命
with an extra race.
多赛一场
So, do not hold back.
所以, 不要保留
Great Britain's the team to watch in our heat.
英国队是我们这组值得关注的队伍
Bobby, not another Poughkeepsie.
鲍比, 别再来波基普西那招了
They won't fade like Cal,
它们不会像加州队那样后程乏力的
so never let them get more than two lengths up.
所以绝不能让他们领先超过两个艇位
Fellas, you've earned this.
伙计们, 这是你们应得的
They don't give gold medals for style.
他们不会为风格颁发金牌
All that matters is how fast you are on the water.
唯一重要的是你们在水上的速度有多快
And nobody here is faster.
这里没人比你们更快
Legs through!
蹬腿！
And the Americans are already leading
美国人已经领先
by half a boat over Great Britain
大不列颠半个艇位
and looking for more.
优势还在变大
Followed by France and Czechoslovakia.
法国和捷克斯洛伐克紧随其后
In, through! In, through!
破 划！破 划！
Stroke Ran Laurie
领桨员冉·劳里
is digging furiously for the British boat.
正在疯狂地挖掘英国艇的速度
But the Americans
但是美国人
are pouring it on now, extending their lead.
现在正在大举进攻, 扩大领先优势
Eyes up. In, through!
抬头 破 划
And through!
划
And with only 100 meters to go,
只剩 100 米了
the Americans could be closing in on an Olympic record.
美国人可能正在接近奥运会纪录
Eyes up!
抬头
Six minutes point eight seconds.
六分八秒
A new Olympic record!
新的奥运纪录！
The United States has won!
美国赢了！
You all right? Hey, you know we won?
你还好吗？嘿, 你知道我们赢了吗？
- Don, are you okay? - You know we won, right? Huh?
- 唐, 你还好吗？- 你知道我们赢了, 对吧？嗯？
- Hey. - Come on. Come on.
- 嘿 - 来吧
Good race.
精彩的比赛
Olympic record's a nice start.
奥运纪录是个好的开始
But all that does is get us into the race that matters.
但这一切只是为了让我们进入真正重要的比赛
Nobody is gonna remember you set a record at a preliminary.
没有人会记得你在预赛中创下的记录
Now...
现在...
let's go see what we're up against.
让我们去看看我们要对付的是谁
Good job.
干得好
Way to go. Way to go.
干得好 干得好
Good work, boys.
干得好, 孩子们
Singles, doubles,
单人赛 双人赛
fours, they haven't lost a race yet.
四人赛 他们还没有输过一场
Fast.
快
Don, come on.
唐, 来吧
Hey, come on.
嘿, 走吧
You all right?
你没事吧？
Coach! Coach!
教练 教练！
- You okay? - Mm-hmm. I'm just worn out.
- 你还好吗？- 没事 我只是累坏了
Thank you, Doctor. Thanks for your help.
谢谢你 医生 谢谢你的帮助
What's the word?
怎么说？
Some kind of bug. They're not sure what.
某种虫子 他们不确定是什么
Right now, he's very dehydrated.
现在, 他脱水严重
He needs rest.
他需要休息
And y'all stay away from him for the next 24 hours.
接下来的24小时, 你们都离他远点
We can't afford losing anybody else.
我们不能再失去任何人了
What do you mean, "losing"?
你说 "失去" 是什么意思？
If he's still like this in two days, he's not racing.
如果两天后他还是这样, 他就不能参加比赛了
Lane assignments for the finals.
决赛航道分配
You can't change the rules
你不能在比赛中间
in the middle of a competition!
改变规则
The fastest qualifiers earn the favored lanes.
最快的预赛选手优先选择航道
That is the way it's always been.
一直就是这样
And we posted the best time,
我们创造了最好的记录
and you've gone and stuck us on the outside.
你却把我们困在外面
This was the lane formula the committee decided on.
这是奥委会决定的航道分配公式
When? Right after your squad
什么时候？就在你们队
posted the slowest qualifying time?
划出最慢的排位时间之后？
Be careful of your accusations, Coach Ulbrickson.
小心你的指控, 乌尔布里克森教练
You've seen the winds on that course and you know
你见过航道上的风, 你知道
there's a two-length disadvantage when it blows.
顶风时, 有两个长度的劣势
I'm sure your crew will manage.
我相信你的艇员们会处理好的
The forecasters expect a calm day.
天气预报预计今天会风平浪静
Well...
嗯...
We'll protest this.
我们对此表示抗议
Noted. And good luck.
记下了 祝你好运
All right. Listen up, boys.
好了 听好了 孩子们
It's a tough lane, so you gotta start quick.
这条航道很难走, 所以你们开始时得快点
You gotta keep them in sight.
必须让他们在你的视线范围内
That wind will be blocked for the last 500 meters.
最后 500 米那里 风会被挡住
And that's your shot.
这就是你们的机会
That's where you're gonna take 'em,
这就是你们拿下他们的地方
but only if you keep 'em in sight.
但前提是 你们得让他们保持在视线范围内
Listen, every one of those teams
听着, 每一支球队
have trained their whole lives for this moment.
为了这一刻, 他们训练了一辈子
They're all legacies.
它们都是富家子
We're not.
我们不是
Row for your country.
为了祖国
Row for each other.
为了彼此
Row for that one moment when everything
为了一切不利因素
that's stacked against you can take a back seat.
都退避三舍的那一刻
For what it's worth, I'm proud of you boys.
无论结果如何, 我都为你们感到骄傲
All right, push off.
好了, 出发吧
What?
什么？
Nothin'
没事
They might as well have stuck us
他们还不如把我们扔
out on the North Atlantic.
在北大西洋上
Thousands of people are taking their seats,
成千上万的人正在入座
gathered for the Men's Eights finals.
男子组八人决赛
The world's six best rowing teams
世界上最好的六支赛艇队
in one last race for the gold.
为金牌进行最后的角逐
Germany, Italy, Hungary
德国 意大利 匈牙利
Germany has taken gold in singles, doubles, and fours,
德国在单人 双人和四人比赛中摘得金牌
and they're looking for a sweep.
他们正在追求大满贯
Switzerland, Great Britain, and the United States
瑞士 英国和美国
round out the six.
位列前六
The boys from Washington so close
来自华盛顿的男孩们如此接近于
to bringing an Olympic title back to Seattle.
将奥运冠军带回西雅图
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！
Don, you okay?
唐, 你还好吗？
You got this, Don, all right?
你能行的, 唐, 好吗？
Hey, what'd he say?
嘿, 他说什么？
All right. Come on, let's win this.
好吧 来吧, 让我们赢下这一场
Oars ready.
桨准备好了
Come on.
来吧
All right, we got two lengths of wind
好吧, 我们有两段风
to make up on this bunch.
来弥补这差距
So, we start at 38.
所以, 我们从 38 拍开始
Bobby! Bobby!
鲍比 鲍比
Shit! Row! Row!
妈的！划！
Come on.
来吧
Oh, God! He couldn't hear him.
哦 上帝啊 他听不到
The Americans have stumbled out of the gate,
美国人一出场就跌跌撞撞
already a full boat behind.
已经落到了最后
Legs through.
蹬腿
All right, now move to 30.
好的, 现在换到 30 拍
Go! In, through.
走！破 划
Legs through!
蹬腿
In, through! In!
破 划 破
All right. We got 38!
好吧 我们有38拍
Give me 40!
给我40拍
In, through!
破 划
In, through! Go!
破 划 上
Come on, Don, pick it up.
快点, 唐, 加速
In the legs! In, through!
腿用力 破 划
In, through!
破 划
- In, through! - It's time to move!
- 破 划！- 是时候行动了
Come on, Don.
来吧, 唐
Go, Don!
去, 唐
Come on, boys.
来吧, 孩子们
Germany is just behind Italy,
德国仅次于意大利
followed by Great Britain.
英国紧随其后
The U.S. still in last, well behind Hungary.
美国仍然排在最后, 远远落后于匈牙利
Give me more! Gotta have more!
给我加速！必须加速
Come on, Don. Give me 40.
来吧 唐 给我 40 拍
In the legs.
腿用力
Push it, Don. Come on, Don!
加油 唐 加油 唐
Now would be a good time, Hume!
现在是个好时机, 休姆
Come on, Don! Pick it up!
来吧, 唐！振作起来
Don, come on.
唐 来吧
Come on, Don.
来吧, 唐
Gotta give me 40. You have it.
给我 40 拍 你可以的
Give it to me.
把它给我
Come on, give me 40.
来吧, 给我 40 拍
Come on, Don.
来吧, 唐
Come on!
来吧
Don!
唐
Don! Come on!
唐 来吧
Every morning, every evening
每天清晨, 每天傍晚
Ain't we got fun?
我们玩得开心吗？
Not much money, oh, but honey
钱不多, 哦, 但是亲爱的
Ain't we got...
我们不是有...吗？
That's right, Don! Give me 40!
没错 唐给我 40 拍
Go! Through!
去吧 划
Legs through!
蹬腿
Eyes up!
抬头
Stay low!
放低！
- Stay loose! - And here comes
- 放松 - 来了
the United States with a burst.
爆裂的美国
Row!
摇
As one!
同步
Nearing the 500-meter mark,
接近 500 米大关
the Americans have caught up
美国人赶上了
to the Hungarian and Swiss teams.
匈牙利队和瑞士队
Stay!
保持
And through! In, through!
划 破 划
The Americans have overtaken
美国人已经超越
the Swiss and the Hungarian boats.
瑞士艇和匈牙利艇
Germany and Italy share the lead,
德国和意大利共同领先
with Great Britain trailing.
英国紧随其后
Legs loose!
腿放松
In, through!
破 划
In and through!
Four! Five!
四 五！
In, through!
破 划
Give me 42!
给我 42 拍
Now!
现在
In, through!
破 划
Breathe!
呼吸！
Legs through! In, through!
蹬腿 破 划
Fifteen more! In!
还有 15 桨！划
Come on. Through!
来吧 划
Ten more!
再来十桨
Shoulders down and loose.
肩膀向下, 放松
Stand tall!
抬高
In, through!
破 划
And the Americans continue strong,
美国人继续强悍
moving past Great Britain and headed for third.
超越英国队, 获得第三名
The U.S. is moving into medal position.
美国正在向奖牌位置迈进
Through! Eyes up!
划！抬头
In, through!
破 划
Give me 46!
给我 46 拍
Go!
冲
300 meters, and the Americans
300 米, 美国人
have pulled even!
追上了！
The boats are three across now.
现在三条艇齐头并进
250 meters to go.
还剩250米
Come on, come on, come on.
来吧, 来吧, 来吧
Legs through!
蹬腿
It's a three-boat race.
这是三艇角逐
Who's going to break?
谁将会胜出？
It's Germany, Italy.
是德国, 意大利
Italy, Germany.
意大利 德国
The U.S. and Italy.
美国和意大利
It's just too close.
太接近了
Stay low!
放低
100 meters to go.
还剩100米
It's neck and neck.
不相上下
Come on.
来吧
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！
Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！德国！德国！
In, through!
破 划
Give it everything! Go!
倾尽全力！冲
Stay central!
保持中心位置！
Eyes up!
抬头
As one!
同步
Off the man in front of you!
跟上你面前的人
In, through!
破 划
Go! In, through!
去吧 破 划
Eyes up!
抬头
In the legs!
腿用力
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国！
Germany, Italy, America.
德国 意大利 美国
Deutschland! Deutschland!
德国！德国
And that's it!
就这样！
That's it!
就是这样！
The results are just too close for this reporter to tell.
结果太接近了, 记者无法判断
Come on.
来吧
Who won?
谁赢了？
The German fans believe
德国粉丝相信
they've got their sixth win of these 1936 Olympics.
是他们赢得了 1936 年奥运会的第六场胜利
We can only sit and wait for the results.
我们只能坐等结果
Did you see?
你看到了吗？
America.
美国
The United States has won the gold!
美国队赢得了金牌！
Good job, Johnny.
干得好, 约翰尼
We did it, boys!
我们成功了, 孩子们！
Come on!
来吧
One hell of a stroke.
激动人心的一桨
America has done it!
美国做到了！
They've won the gold!
他们赢得了金牌
Hell of a race.
真是一场精彩的比赛
- You did it, Al. You did it. - I'm proud of you.
- 你做到了 艾尔 你做到了 - 我为你骄傲
We did it.
我们做到了
How about this, huh?
这个怎么样？
Mm-hmm. How about this?
嗯 这个怎么样？
Anything you'd like to say about those boys, Al?
关于那些男孩, 你有什么想说的吗, 艾尔？
They are the finest I ever saw seated in a shell.
他们是我见过的最棒的艇员
Not bad, huh, fellas?
不错吧, 伙计们？
Did you see that?
你看到了吗？
Boat pushed me right into the bank.
艇直接把我推到了岸边
- Look at this. - Don't worry, we'll fix it.
- 看看这个 - 别担心, 我们会修好的
Hey, Grandpa?
嘿, 爷爷？
You think someday I can row crew?
你觉得有一天我会划艇吗？
Well, you gotta keep at it.
嗯, 你得坚持下去
Did you like rowing eight-man crew?
你喜欢八人划艇吗？
- Eight? - Yeah.
- 八个人 - 对
We were never eight.
我们从来不是八个人
We were one.
我们是一个人
《赛艇男孩》
字幕:Dex7er  公众号:值得看的